【music】
【音楽】
Academia Sinica's Knowledge Experience in August Kebo Lectures and Speeches Begin
8月に中央研究院の知識体験、Keboの講義と講演が始まる
We invite Vice President Huang Jingxin to host for us
黄景新副大統領を主催者として迎えます
【applause】
【拍手】
First of all, on behalf of Academia Sinica, welcome all distinguished guests
まず、中央研究院を代表して、ご来賓の皆様を歓迎いたします。
Well, today is Professor Ying Qingsun's lecture
さて、今日はYing Qingsun先生の講義です
So this is also a speech he gave before he retired.
つまり、これは彼が引退する前に行ったスピーチでもあります。
But don't worry, he didn't just retire
でも緊張しないでください、彼はただ引退したわけではありません
He will retire in 2021
彼は2021年に引退する予定です
so i just
だから私はただ
I was also very nervous just now, such an important scholar is going to retire soon
私も今とても緊張していました、そのような重要な学者がもうすぐ退職することになっています
I'm not ready yet
まだ準備できていない
I am in charge of major research in the humanities and social sciences
人文社会科学の主要な研究を担当しています
So I'm right about this
だからこれについては私が正しい
Special care for the dynamics of our outstanding academics
私たちの優れた学者の力学に特別な配慮をする
then let me introduce
それでは今から紹介します
Shadow Youth Professor
影青春教授
Maybe some people think of him as a very herdsman
おそらく一部の人は彼を非常に牧畜民だと思っているでしょう
know him well
彼をよく知っています
But I still have to be reasonable
しかし、それでも私は合理的でなければなりません
say a few words
いくつかの言葉を言ってください
Professor Naying Youth
ナイイング・ユース教授
he is american
彼はアメリカ人です
Ph.D., Department of Sociology, Minsota Zhouli University
ミンソタ州周里大学社会学部博士号
Now it is the Institute of Sociology of our school
今は私たちの学校の社会学研究所です
Distinguished Researcher
特別研究員
The specially-appointed researcher is from the university.
特任研究員は本学出身です。
lecture professor meaning
講義教授の意味
What about research interests?
研究上の関心についてはどうでしょうか？
major in family sociology
家族社会学を専攻
youth development
青少年の育成
women role
女性の役割
Chen Dannai International
チェン・ダンナイ・インターナショナル
Member of the Executive Committee of the Sociological Society ISA
ISA社会学会実行委員会委員
Chair of the Family Research Committee
家族研究委員会委員長
Currently serving as the editor of several domestic and foreign academic journals
現在、国内外の複数の学術雑誌の編集者を務める。
Editorial Board and Advisors
編集委員会とアドバイザー
Host and participate in various academic projects
さまざまな学術プロジェクトを主催し、参加する
Including the period from 1991 to 1994
1991年から1994年までの期間を含む
Survey on Social Image in Taiwan
台湾の社会イメージに関する調査
2004 to 2007
2004年から2007年
Refers to the intergenerational inheritance of virtual values
仮想価値の世代間の継承を指します。
and from 1997 to 2020
そして1997年から2020年まで
The growth history of Taiwanese teenagers, etc.
台湾の青少年の成長史など
his scholarly works
彼の学術著作
Focus on family studies and youth studies
家族研究と青少年研究に焦点を当てる
Psychological Welfare Included
精神福祉込み
Israel Youth 2013
Israel Youth 2013 年
forthcoming
今後の
Qian Jun Taiwan
チェン・ジュン 台湾
Academic Issues of Feminist
フェミニストの学術的問題
What about today, Professor Ying Qingchun?
イン・チンチュン教授、今日はどうですか？
will explain to us that there is a hospital
病院があることを説明してくれる
A long-term research project driven by society
社会主導による長期研究プロジェクト
is from 2000
2000年からです
Continue to track the progress of Guoyi and Guoshan
Guoyi と Guoshan の進捗状況を追跡し続ける
teen growth trajectory
十代の成長の軌跡
so we have someone here
ここに誰かがいます
Those in the investigation have become adults
調査対象者は大人になった
the young man's child
若者の子供
This long-term follow-up
今回の長期フォローアップは
The Growth Process of Taiwanese Teenagers
台湾の10代の若者の成長過程
and social context research
および社会的背景の調査
Attempt to explore family education from it
そこから家庭教育を探る試み
interaction with society
社会との関わり
and the difficulty of constructing localized research
地域に特化した研究を構築することの難しさ
It is hoped that the results of the study
研究結果が期待される
Proposed to influence the youth of the society
社会の若者に影響を与えることを提案
Important Factors in the Growth Process
成長プロセスにおける重要な要素
His speech must be wonderful
彼のスピーチは素晴らしいに違いない
Let's applaud Dr. Ying
イン博士に拍手を送りましょう
Thanks
ありがとう
you are the one, aren't you?
あなたがその人ですよね？
you have to stand
あなたは立たなければなりません
It doesn't matter if you can sit here
ここに座れるかどうかは関係ない
Standing like this
こうやって立っている
open it first
まず開けてください
Thank you Vice President Huang
黄副社長に感謝します
It's really an honor to have the opportunity to represent the research group
研究グループを代表する機会をいただけて本当に光栄です
Come share our research results with you
私たちの研究結果をぜひ共有してください
Last time at this place was June 2010
最後にこの場所を訪れたのは 2010 年 6 月でした
At that time, the first phase of our follow-up study
当時、追跡調査の第一段階は
just came to an end
ちょうど終わったばかり
so i'm joking
だから冗談だよ
Our humanities and social sciences seem to have to be taught every 10 years
私たちの人文科学と社会科学は10年ごとに教えなければならないようです
So I probably won't have time to report the update to you next year
なので、来年はアップデートを報告する時間がおそらくないでしょう
So when I was preparing this speech myself,
それで、私自身がこのスピーチを準備していたとき、
I am very grateful
私は非常に感謝しています
then later
じゃあ後で
Because I really want to share such rich results with you.
このような豊かな結果をぜひ皆さんと共有したいと思っているからです。
hang again
またハングアップ
So I keep changing the powerpoint to 6:10
そこで、パワーポイントを 6:10 に変更し続けます。
so now what
んで、どうする
I try my best to speak
頑張って話そうとする
Please cheer up everyone
皆さんも元気を出してください
I speak faster and faster
私はますます速く話します
that's
それは
I will try my best to make everyone understand
皆様にご理解いただけるよう全力を尽くします
especially i'm glad to know
特に知って嬉しいです
Some of the respondents to our straight talk in-depth interviews
私たちの率直なトークの詳細なインタビューに答えた人の一部
here today
今日ここに
i don't know where you are
あなたがどこにいるのか分かりません
but hope you know
でも知っていただければ幸いです
Your academic contribution is very great
あなたの学術的貢献は非常に素晴らしいです
Thanks
ありがとう
good
良い
give me this
これをください
where do i press
どこを押せばいいですか
good
良い
Simply put, before starting
簡単に言えば、始める前に
I want to represent
代表したい
Our research group is mainly composed of sociologists and social psychologists
私たちの研究グループは主に社会学者と社会心理学者で構成されています
So
それで
what our research cares
私たちの研究が重視していること
I said that we are often more concerned about structural factors
私たちは構造的要因をより懸念することが多いと言いました
Personal factors are also important
個人的な要素も重要
But we may be more concerned with structural factors
しかし、私たちは構造的要因のほうに関心があるかもしれません
People like to see some short-term effects
人々は短期的な効果を見ることを好みます
We pay more attention to some long-term effects
私たちは長期的な影響にさらに注目しています
in addition
加えて
cultural norms
文化的規範
Great influence on people
人々に大きな影響を与える
Or personal education income, etc.
あるいは個人の教育収入など。
How high is this personal resource?
この個人リソースはどのくらいのレベルですか?
Then these influences
それから、これらの影響
There are also some data for our reference
参考となるデータもあります
I simply use an example to illustrate
説明するために例を使用しただけです
I think maybe everyone will understand
たぶんみんなも分かってくれると思うよ
We all know that divorce research is very important
離婚調査が非常に重要であることは誰もが知っています
Probably the world has
おそらく世界はそうしているでしょう
More than thousands of academic research reports
数千を超える学術研究レポート
Most divorce studies are
離婚に関する研究のほとんどは、
Focus on the reasons for divorce between husband and wife
夫婦の離婚原因に焦点を当てる
Then tell you that the relationship is not good
それから関係が良くないことを伝えてください
Because they have different money levels, etc.
お金のレベルなどが違うからです。
this is very important
これはとても重要です
However, sociological research is more concerned with structural factors
ただし、社会学的研究は構造的要因により重点を置いています。
That is to say, when the husband and wife are two people
つまり、夫婦が二人のとき、
As soon as it is shown, the difference in education level is greater
表れた時点で学歴の差はもっと大きい
The greater the difference in financial background between the two growth backgrounds
2つの成長背景の財務背景の差が大きいほど
or his whole body
または彼の全身
The greater the difference in life experience, the greater the difference in these structural experiences
人生経験の違いが大きければ大きいほど、これらの構造的経験の違いも大きくなります
The probability of his divorce has increased significantly
彼の離婚の可能性は大幅に上昇した
So let's say it again, what we're going to say later
だからもう一度言いましょう、後で言うことは
All findings do not refer to a single person
すべての調査結果は 1 人の人物に関するものではありません
Rather, it is a pattern that is pronounced across the majority
むしろ、それは大多数の人に顕著なパターンです
So there are always some surprises
だからいつもいくつかの驚きがあります
These journalism scholars are very interested
これらのジャーナリズム学者は非常に興味を持っています
To report these special circumstances
このような特殊な状況を報告するには
We want to know too, but we want to know more
私たちも知りたい、でももっと知りたい
what most people look like
ほとんどの人がどのように見えるか
But I just said that we are right about the structural factors
しかし、私は構造的要因については正しいと言いました。
Because Huang Fu is here
黄福がここにいるから
There's nothing we can do when we meet historians
歴史家に会っても何もできない
Because, our...
なぜなら、私たちの...
like that divorce study tells us
離婚研究が私たちに示しているように
when the country is at war
国が戦争状態にあるとき
That divorce rate is soaring
離婚率が急上昇している
Fortunately , wars don't happen every day
幸いなことに、戦争は毎日起こるわけではありません
That is the structural factor at least exists
それが構造的要因です、少なくとも存在します
probably like this
おそらくこんな感じ
In today's report, I will probably focus on the first two aspects.
今日のレポートでは、おそらく最初の 2 つの側面に焦点を当てたいと思います。
Because it's a...
それは...
Long-term research, especially with many colleagues among us and our sample
長期にわたる研究、特に私たちとサンプルの多くの同僚との研究
I will explain the whole research plan to you.
研究計画全体について説明させていただきます。
Then I try to succinctly divide the findings of our research into three parts
次に、私たちの研究結果を 3 つの部分に簡潔に分割してみます。
In terms of family, in terms of education, in terms of marriage and childbearing in this generation
この時代の家族のこと、教育のこと、結婚・出産のこと。
I am very grateful that this project over the years is mainly from the Academia Sinica Theme Research Project
このプロジェクトは主に中央研究院の長年にわたるテーマ研究プロジェクトからのものであり、非常に感謝しています。
There is also support from the Ministry of Science and Technology, the former National Science Council, and social institutes.
科学技術省、旧国家学術会議、社会機関からの支援もあります。
Fine fee support can only continue until now
微課金サポートは今までしか継続できない
Our research team, this is the second phase
私たちの研究チーム、これは第二段階です
In the first stage, there are some professors such as Fuyang Zhi who have participated in the
第一段階では扶陽志などの教授が参加している。
I made this Star sign because I was a postdoctoral fellow in this project
この星座を作ったのは、私がこのプロジェクトの博士研究員だったからです。
For example, Fan Ganghua, associate professor of Soochow University, is on it
たとえば、蘇州大学のファン・ガンファ准教授はこれに取り組んでいます。
And these are now assistant professors
そして彼らは今では助教授です
There are different ranks and different schools
階級も学校も違う
Simply put, TYP
簡単に言えば、TYP
I call simplicity TYP, it studies the master
私はそれをシンプルなTYPと呼んでいます、それはマスターを研究します
can be divided into three
3つに分けることができます
one is that we want to know
1つは私たちが知りたいことです
The growth trajectory of contemporary young people
現代の若者の成長の軌跡
We are definitely not the first research team in Taiwan
私たちは決して台湾初の研究チームではありません
do this topic
この話題をやる
New Women Scholars
新しい女性奨学生
they put a lot of emphasis on some development
彼らはある種の開発に重点を置いている
They may go from elementary school to junior high school
小学校から中学校に進学することもある
Or from middle school to high school
あるいは中学から高校まで
i know on the biological side
生物学的側面では知っています
There are also many people doing his fertility development
彼の生殖能力開発を行っている人もたくさんいます
But we are from the perspective of social science
しかし、私たちは社会科学の観点から考えています
Especially sociology and family studies orientation
特に社会学と家族学のオリエンテーション
go see this thing
これを見に行ってください
The second schedule of our positioning
ポジショニングの第 2 スケジュール
from a life course perspective
ライフコースの観点から
from early teens
十代前半から
traced all the way to his young adulthood
彼の青年期まで遡った
So it goes through several important life stages
したがって、いくつかの重要なライフステージを通過します
The third
第3
Of course we want to see
もちろん見たいです
Indigenous development model
先住民族の開発モデル
The vast majority of members were educated in the United States
会員の大多数は米国で教育を受けた
So for the study of American adolescents
アメリカの青少年の研究では
Their biggest priority is probably nothing more than drug use.
彼らの最大の優先事項はおそらく薬物使用に他なりません。
with sex
セックスあり
But then we kept thinking
しかしその後私たちは考え続けました
our middle school kids
私たちの中学生の子供たち
Is this his main life focus
これが彼の人生の主な焦点ですか
It does not seem
そうではないようです
So in the last study
それで、最後の研究では
I will specifically report to you
具体的にご報告させていただきます
Stress cram school results for students and more
ストレス塾の生徒の実績など
Actually that's what they really are
実際、それが彼らの本当の姿なのです
second way of life
第二の生き方
Then we also hope that in the end we can
そして、最終的にはできることを願っています。
Influence of social and cultural norms seen in multiple growth trajectories
複数の成長軌道に見られる社会的および文化的規範の影響
So this is what I will say quickly about these three one by one.
それでは、これら 3 つについて 1 つずつ簡単に説明します。
The growth trajectory of young people
若者たちの成長の軌跡
Have social context, cultural norms, and life experience
社会的背景、文化的規範、人生経験を持っている
We have been fortunate to have
私たちは幸運なことに、
just in the whole from
ちょうど全体から
From collectivism to individualism
集団主義から個人主義へ
Intergenerational values ​​and attitudes
世代を超えた価値観と態度
We hear it all over the place
あちこちで聞こえてきます
So we just use a scientific evidence to see
したがって、科学的証拠を使用して確認するだけです
what is he
彼は何ですか
In this stage, from 13 years old to 32 years old, there are school diversion and job stratification
13 歳から 32 歳までのこの段階では、学校の転用と職業の階層化が行われます。
Then does the young man want to live with his parents, and does he continue to live with his parents after he gets married?
では、その青年は両親と暮らしたいのでしょうか、また結婚後も両親と暮らし続けるのでしょうか？
Then when will he leave home? Are there any regional differences? Are there resource considerations?
では、彼はいつ家を出るのでしょうか?地域差はありますか?資源に関する考慮事項はありますか?
More importantly, we noticed that when we started, we said we were going to design a scale called parental control of children.
さらに重要なのは、私たちが始めたときに、子供のペアレンタルコントロールと呼ばれるスケールを設計するつもりだと述べたことに気づきました。
At that time, the professor of the University of California proposed the concept and there was no scale, so how do you talk about management?
当時はカリフォルニア大学の教授が提案したもので、スケールもありませんでしたが、経営についてはどのように語られていますか？
As a result, I didn’t expect our channel to follow all the way. The interviewees among us will know that we often ask you to change it occasionally.
結果として、私たちのチャンネルが最後まで続くとは予想していませんでした。私たちのインタビュー対象者は、私たちが時々チャンネルを変更してほしいとよくお願いしていることを知っているでしょう。
I found out that Chinese parents, especially Taiwanese parents, still manage their children until they are in their 30s.
中国人の親、特に台湾人の親は、30代になるまで子供を管理していることが分かりました。
He may say that I don't care about it, I only have one thought that I care about, but more than half of them still continue to care about it.
彼は、私はそんなことは気にしていない、私が気にしている考えは 1 つだけだ、と言うかもしれませんが、彼らの半数以上はまだそれを気にし続けています。
In this case, you tell him that children like to be self-reliant
この場合、子供たちは自立するのが好きなのだと彼に伝えます。
Self-reliance is different from self-reliance in Europe and the United States
自立は欧米の自立とは違う
because for all parents
すべての親のためだから
as long as the child wants to read
子供が読みたい限り
I can afford it
余裕があります
It is my responsibility that you read at the age of 30
30歳になってから読むのは私の責任です
I think the parents here will probably say Amei
ここの親はおそらくアメイと言うと思います
This has already begun to be completely different from European and American societies.
これはすでにヨーロッパやアメリカの社会とはまったく異なり始めています。
So it's worth our research
したがって、研究する価値があります
Then the localized development model
次に、ローカライズされた開発モデル
like we even asked some families about their parenting strategies
一部の家族に子育て戦略について尋ねたように、
Last time I also reported to you
前回もご報告させていただきましたが
parents will say
親は言うだろう
Come on, junior high school kids
さあ、中学生たちよ
i don't watch tv
テレビを見ません
I don't go out either
私も出ません
I just concentrate on feeding him chicken soup
私は彼にチキンスープを与えることに集中する
But kids don't feel like that
でも子供たちはそんなこと感じないよ
As a child, I feel that my parents have been controlling me
子供の頃、両親が私をコントロールしてきたと感じる
did you talk on the phone
電話で話しましたか
have you dated anyone
誰かとデートしたことがありますか
so same problem
同じ問題です
You put it on the parents and put it on the child
あなたはそれを親に着せ、子供にも着せます
You can compare the answers when you ask them together.
質問に対する答えを比較することができます
probably like this
おそらくこんな感じ
That's a long-term follow-up study
それは長期追跡調査です
At the beginning there were about 5,000 people
当初は5000人くらいいたんですが
noodle shop
麺屋
In which we carried out several years later
数年後に実施したのは
We feel research
研究を感じる
It seems to give a very important structure
非常に重要な構造を与えているようです
But sometimes what everyone wants to see is flesh and blood
でも時々、誰もが見たいのは生身の人間だ
This flesh and blood is often what straightforward research can provide
多くの場合、この血肉は直接的な研究によって得られるものです
But if you only do literal research
しかし、文字通りの研究だけを行うのであれば、
In fact, what do you represent
実際、あなたは何を表していますか
Everyone often has such a question
誰もがよくこのような質問をします
so we are lucky
だから私たちは幸運です
Some of our more than 5,000 samples can be found
5,000 を超えるサンプルの一部をご覧いただけます
Yeah, do some in-depth interviews with teenagers about the belly.
そうだ、十代の若者たちにお腹について詳しくインタビューしてみよう。
so everyone can see
みんなが見れるように
Our samples are Guo 1 and Guo 3 in 2000
私たちのサンプルは 2000 年の Guo 1 と Guo 3 です。
The third year of junior high school was the last candidate
中学3年生が最終候補だった
entrance examination system
入学試験制度
Country one is the new system
国 1 は新しいシステムです
Then I reported to you last time today.
それでは、本日前回ご報告させていただきました。
there is a difference
違いがあります
We later discovered that under the old system
後でわかったのですが、古いシステムでは
It should be said that under the new system
新制度のもとではこう言うべきだろう
Household income in the top 25%
世帯収入上位25%
Chances of attending star high schools are remarkably high
スター高校に進学できる可能性が非常に高い
So it is true that the teaching reform brought some
したがって、教育改革が何らかの成果をもたらしたのは事実です。
greater inequality
より大きな不平等
We predict the same
私たちも同じことを予測します
That first stage is
その最初の段階は、
20000 to 2009
20000 年から 2009 年まで
We started in 1998
1998年にスタートしました
First bathroom in 1999
1999年に最初のバスルームが完成
Then in 2000 a formal investigation was conducted
そして2000年に正式な調査が行われた
By 2009
2009年までに
They are basically the equivalent of a university
基本的には大学と同等です
when you graduated from college
あなたが大学を卒業したとき
We were all debating whether to continue
続けるかどうかみんなで話し合った
Because I'm getting a little tired
少し疲れてきたので
will be tired
疲れるだろう
But I didn't expect a phone call to explain the law
でも、法律の説明のために電話がかかってくるとは思わなかった
It came back very well
とてもよく戻ってきました
We agreed to get our spirits up and do it again
私たちは元気を出してもう一度やることに同意しました
Guys, let's take this survey
皆さん、アンケートに答えてみましょう
we have a time every friday
毎週金曜日には時間があります
52 weeks a year and at least 40 more weeks
年間 52 週間、さらに少なくとも 40 週間
We are all talking about paper coupons
みんなでクーポンのことを話しています
I brought such a result to Hong Kong
こんな成果を香港にもたらした
Bring to Shanghai Bring to Beijing
上海に持っていく 北京に持っていく
say unconditionally
無条件に言う
hope you do let us compare
ぜひ比較させてください
They study the group. After each group discussion,
彼らはグループで勉強し、各グループでディスカッションした後、
Let's just say it's a bit difficult. It's too hard.
ちょっと難しいと言いましょうか、難しすぎます。
And then asked me how did you do it
そしてどうやってやったのかと尋ねました
I'm just kidding, it's true
冗談だよ、本当だよ
Let me say that you are young and ignorant
言っておきますが、あなたは若くて無知です
If you think you can do it, start doing it
できると思ったらやってみよう
Now that I think about it, I'm really happy
今思うと本当に幸せでした
There is a group of like-minded friends who have come to this day
今日まで同じ志を持った友人のグループが来ました
So what about our second phase?
では、第 2 フェーズはどうなるでしょうか?
adult sample from this time in 2011
2011 年のこの時期の成人向けサンプル
Then we will combine the students from the first country and the third country
次に、第一か国の学生と第三国の学生を結合します。
adult sample
アダルトサンプル
So to put it simply
簡単に言えば
At that time, we surveyed two groups of samples almost every year
当時、私たちはほぼ毎年 2 つのグループのサンプルを調査していました
The questions asked by your first-year and third-year students are different
1年生と3年生では質問が異なります
Junior high school is different
中学校は違うよ
So every year we have to design a new topic
したがって、毎年新しいトピックを設計する必要があります
Then at that time add one of the parents
その時点で、親の 1 人を追加します
Also add a tutor
家庭教師も追加
you can see
見ることができます
Then later pooling the adult samples
その後、成人のサンプルをプールする
We decided we didn't need to do it every three years
3年ごとに行う必要はないと判断しました
Then you see when the parents started to enter
そして、いつ両親が入り始めたかがわかります
Average age 42
平均年齢42歳
at the end of the first phase
最初のフェーズの終わりに
Average age of parents is 52
親の平均年齢は52歳
We are very pleased that Vice President Huang of Zhongyuan Institute
中原研究所の黄副院長の就任を大変嬉しく思います。
with special support
特別支持下
We just sent our IRB to the hospital yesterday
昨日治験審査委員会を病院に送ったところです
We were still tweaking our questionnaire last week
先週もアンケートを調整中だった
This fall we will be
この秋、私たちはこうなります
Parents with an average age of 62
平均年齢62歳の両親
It's parents who are young and old
老いも若きも親たちだ
Do the sixth follow-up survey
6回目の追跡調査を実施する
Because in their old age
なぜなら彼らは老後だから
relationship with acknowledgment of interactions among children
子ども間の交流の承認との関係
This is not the same as European and American society
これはヨーロッパやアメリカの社会と同じではありません
we're not just going to discuss
ただ議論するだけではありません
Does the concept of school ethics still exist?
学校倫理という概念は今でも存在するのでしょうか？
school morality
学校倫理
is already in your culture
すでにあなたの文化の中にあります
How do you adjust and perform
どのように調整してパフォーマンスを行うのか
This is the part we are very interested in
これは私たちが非常に興味を持っている部分です
So we basically look like this
基本的には次のようになります
Then this is to let everyone know
それでは皆さんにお知らせです
because at this time we say
なぜなら現時点では私たちはこう言うからです
We don't know how long we can go
どれだけ長く続けられるか分かりません
But for our sociology
しかし、私たちの社会学にとっては、
It's important to be gendered
性別が重要である
social class differences
社会階級の違い
So we believe that this northern Taiwan can
したがって、私たちはこの台湾北部ができると信じています。
These three places allow us to
これら 3 つの場所により、
to achieve such a purpose
そのような目的を達成する
So the sample we start with
それで、私たちが始めるサンプルは
Probably the structure is like this
たぶん構造はこんな感じ
Mentor, each of us asks
メンター、私たち一人一人が尋ねます
One of the parents found out that 70% were mothers
親の一人は、70％が母親であることを知りました
So we want to catch up with dad this year
だから今年はお父さんに追いつきたいです
Would you like to join
ご参加されますか
Principal of that country
あの国の校長
Later, under the suggestion of Academician Lin Nan
その後、学者の林南氏の提案により、
We also supplemented some of their resources
また、リソースの一部を補足しました
Here is our sample
これが私たちのサンプルです
You just believe it must be reliable
それは信頼できるに違いないと信じているだけです
And in the end, what is rare for us is
そして結局、私たちにとって珍しいのは、
we sample the whole class
クラス全体をサンプリングします
How many do you draw in each class
各クラスで何枚描きますか
Come out and sample the class
出てきてクラスを試してみてください
different
違う
Because the whole class is sampled you can follow along
クラス全体がサンプルで提供されるため、一緒に学習することができます
they have a relationship between friends
彼らは友人同士の関係にある
For example, in the last report to you
たとえば、前回のレポートでは、
in that sometimes good class
時々良いクラスで
Compared with this class with poor grades
成績の悪いこのクラスに比べて
Find good students in poor class
成績が悪いクラスから優秀な生徒を見つける
more protected
より保護された
Because these naughty students
なぜなら、このいたずらな生徒たちは
will feel that this good student
この良い生徒は感じるだろう
to protect a little
少しでも守るために
but if it is
しかし、もしそうなら
middle grades
成績中等
Then he gets to medium and he gets affected sometimes
その後、彼は中程度になり、時々影響を受けます
So these are all because you sampled the whole class
これらはすべて、クラス全体をサンプリングしたためです
you can see the difference
違いがわかります
So probably the actual answer rate is of course not bad.
したがって、おそらく実際の正答率は当然悪くありません。
simply speaking
簡単に言えば
using Western algorithms
西洋のアルゴリズムを使用
Our response rate should be considered high
私たちの応答率は高いと考えるべきです
why 102
なぜ102
Because we start from scratch every time
毎回ゼロから始めるから
Just start with 5000
まずは5000から始めてください
Just start from 5000 and start sending from 5000
5000から始めて5000から送信するだけです
But the algorithms in the West are all researched by me this year.
しかし、西洋のアルゴリズムはすべて今年私が研究したものです。
Just compare with last year and see how much I have left
昨年と比較して、どれだけ残っているかを確認してください
That's more than 90
それは90以上です
so we can even chase this place
だからこの場所を追いかけることもできる
It took a lot of effort to chase after we decided
決めたことを追いかけるのは大変な努力だった
ok can continue
わかりました、続けても大丈夫です
Then our questionnaire construction is generally comparable
したがって、私たちのアンケートの構築はほぼ同等です
We also have our own feet
私たちにも自分の足がある
because you want to compare with international
海外と比較したいから
But you have to be like our joint good pressure
しかし、私たちと同じように自分自身の利益を持たなければならないというプレッシャー
This thing must be designed by yourself.
これは自分でデザインする必要があります。
Does anyone have such a topic?
誰かそのような話題はありますか？
So we will design some of these topics
そこで、これらのトピックのいくつかをデザインします
Compared with Xixi, they had these ideas about Fengliang's parents when they were young.
西西と比べて、彼らは幼い頃、鳳梁の両親について次のような考えを持っていました。
is also different
も違います
gender role attitudes
性別役割に対する態度
Ask once for each stage as we do
私たちが行うように、各段階で1回ずつ質問してください
Junior high school, college, adult
中学生、大学生、大人
He is now in his 30s and
彼は現在30代になり、
You can see the change in this little kid from 13 to 31
13歳から31歳までのこの小さな子の変化がわかります
Then his parents asked the exact same question
すると彼の両親も全く同じ質問をしました
you can have a vertical comparison
垂直方向の比較ができる
Parents at the age of 42 and 52
42歳と52歳の両親
Will it affect
影響はありますか
kids now
今の子供たち
Okay, so we have some special problems
さて、特別な問題がいくつかあります
Then I don't know why I thought of doing this in-depth interview
では、なぜこのような詳細なインタビューをしようと思ったのかわかりません
general big plans
一般的な大きな計画
I remember Germany in 2005
2005年のドイツを思い出します
When the National Science Council is about to start their 20,000-person investigation
国家学術会議が2万人規模の調査を開始しようとしているとき
once invited me to speak
一度私を講演に招待したことがある
I'll just talk to them
彼らと話してみるよ
Our planning specially includes the interview of this teammate
私たちの企画には特別にこのチームメイトのインタビューが含まれています
is that we found something
何かを見つけたということですか
you can't quantify
数値化することはできません
I remember hearing that they discussed it for half a year
半年くらい議論したと聞いたのを覚えています
because their psychologists would love to
彼らの心理学者が喜んでそうするからです
But then other scholars decided that it was too difficult
しかしその後、他の学者たちはそれは難しすぎると判断しました
they just give up
彼らはただ諦めるだけだ
So I'm glad we still made it
だからまだ成功してよかった
like in retrospect
振り返ってみたように
how long is this
これはどれくらいですか
As long as the door tells us he's free
ドアが彼を自由だと告げている限り
Manage what time the ends of the earth
地の果てが何時かを管理する
we all cooperate
私たちは皆で協力します
Then two teachers and two assistants went to visit respectively
その後、先生2名とアシスタント2名がそれぞれ訪問に行きました。
Then look at some of their situations
次に、彼らの状況をいくつか見てみましょう
I still remember that time when we saw this girl from Beibei
Beibei のこの女の子を見たときのことを今でも覚えています
parents will tell us
両親が私たちに言うでしょう
The 50,000 yuan we discussed in the end
最終的に話し合った5万元は
Buying her a computer won't repair that roof
彼女にコンピューターを買っても屋根は直らない
Later, he went to the medical department of the National Defense Medical Academy.
その後、防衛医科大学校医学部に進学。
we are really very happy
私たちは本当にとても幸せです
Well, we've published straight talk research
その後、ストレートトークに関する研究を発表しました
Also tell us that between parents and children
親子間のことも教えてください
Correspondence
対応
When the expectations for future education are the same
将来の教育に対する期待が同じ場合
Of course it is best for children to learn
もちろん子どもたちが学ぶのが一番良いのですが、
so this is
それでこれは
The month we discussed in the basement of the Mingzhi Institute
明智秀の地下室で話し合った月
Because everyone wants more samples for their questions
誰もが自分の質問に対してより多くのサンプルを望んでいるからです
that won't work
それはうまくいきません
must be fair
公平でなければなりません
So we use various methods
そこで、さまざまな方法を使います
find these 60 pairs
この 60 ペアを見つけてください
so really being
本当にそうなの
What are you doing today if there is an interviewee
取材対象者がいたら今日は何をするか
we really appreciate you
本当に感謝しています
Because we didn't draw randomly
ランダムに描いたわけではないので
I draw you out according to the rules
ルールに従ってあなたを引き出します
And you promise you think how happy we are
そしてあなたは私たちがどれほど幸せであるか考えると約束します
That's the first phase of the research structure
それが研究体制の第一段階です
I also reported it last time
前回も報告させていただきましたが
Simply put, someone said
簡単に言えば、誰かが言いました
What are your main findings in Phase 1?
フェーズ 1 での主な発見は何ですか?
I said if you really want to talk
本当に話したいならと言いました
We're going to study homeschool community interactions
私たちはホームスクールコミュニティの相互作用を研究するつもりです
As found in many of our papers
私たちの論文の多くに見られるように
Early family experiences do have long-term effects
初期の家族体験は長期的な影響を与える
For example we have 40% look like
たとえば、40% は次のようになります。
He actually lived with his grandparents for a while before he was 12.
実は彼は12歳になるまでしばらく祖父母と一緒に住んでいました。
Three generations living under one roof
一つ屋根の下で暮らす三世代
Let him now have a more positive evaluation in terms of intergenerational relations
世代間関係に関してもっと前向きな評価をしてもらいましょう
but the interesting thing is
しかし興味深いのは
If you live with your grandparents
祖父母と同居している場合
He has negative feelings towards his father
彼は父親に対して否定的な感情を抱いている
I still remember that time
その時のことを今でも覚えています
The editor-in-chief of Xigan in the United States has been asking me to explain this
米国の『Xigan』編集長が私にこれについて説明するように頼んできました。
I said we haven't had a straight talk yet, what should I say?
まだはっきりと話し合っていないと言いましたが、何と言えばいいでしょうか？
I said we could give us a Cruel
クルーエルをあげてもいいって言ったんだ
That is to say, whatever you are in society
つまり、社会の中でどんなことがあっても、
Use a non-traditional atypical living arrangement
非伝統的な非典型的な生活配置を採用する
Actually everyone
実はみんな
The parties involved are aware of this situation
関係者はこの状況を認識している
So when you encounter non-traditional atypical
したがって、非伝統的な非定型的な問題に遭遇したとき、
It's not actually in your best interest
それは実際にはあなたの利益にならない
But I remember we explained it like this
でも、こんな風に説明したのを覚えています
Then the education diversion I will talk about later
それから教育転用については後ほどお話します
Then Leaving Home and Education also published some articles
その後、Leave Home and Education にもいくつかの記事が掲載されました
We found Sakuro
サクロさんを見つけました
The children in Yilan have the most experience away from home
宜蘭の子どもたちは家を離れた経験が最も多い
This is true for employment and education
これは雇用や教育にも当てはまります
Then why start the second
ではなぜ2番目を始めるのか
We say after teens turn 22
10代が22歳になったらと言います
he enters early adulthood
彼は成人期早期に入る
this experience
この経験
And recently this one is prone to cough when talking a lot
そして最近これはよく話すと咳き込みやすくなりました
no matter what
何があっても
This You Track Teen Experiences Into Early Adulthood
これは、成人初期までの 10 代の経験を追跡します
you don't use backtracking
あなたはバックトラッキングを使用しません
It's important that you master it right now
今すぐマスターすることが重要です
And because we've had from middle school to early adulthood
そして、私たちは中学生から成人初期までを過ごしてきたので、
mid term
中期
So it will have different life stages which links
したがって、さまざまなライフステージがあり、それらがリンクされます
We all have some important factors to look at
私たちは皆、注目すべき重要な要素をいくつか持っています
In addition, you compare the differences between the parent and child generations
さらに、親世代と子世代の違いを比較します。
We don't seem to be doing a good job at the moment.
現時点では良い仕事ができていないようです。
But this is where this material can be invaluable
しかし、ここでこの資料が非常に貴重になる可能性があります
So the second stage samples are simply
したがって、第 2 段階のサンプルは単純に
We have a sample of ordinary people and we have conducted a total of three waves of surveys
私たちは一般の人々のサンプルを用意しており、合計 3 回の調査を実施しました。
2011 14 and 17 we all start in October every year
2011 14 と 17 毎年 10 月に始まります
so every other year
だから隔年ごとに
As a result, after returning in 11 years, I got the materials in 12 years
結果、11年ぶりに帰国後、12年ぶりに資料が手に入りました
We found that 7% are married
7％が既婚者であることがわかりました
I remember at that time my heart moved
あの時、心が動いたのを覚えています
Wow, if the spouse survey can be done at this time
うわー、このタイミングで配偶者調査ができるなら
It's like the beginning of his family formation
それは彼の家族形成の始まりのようです
we collect data
私たちはデータを収集します
how precious it is
それはどれほど貴重なことか
I still remember that time our group had a little discussion
私たちのグループが少し話し合ったときのことを今でも覚えています
Professor Zhang Yinghua is still in our advisory committee, and the report says
張英華教授は今も我々の諮問委員会に属しており、報告書にはこう書かれている。
According to the boss
上司によると
just have to do
ただやらなければならない
It's like saying I must buy that dress
そのドレスを買わなければいけないと言っているようなものだ
I still think my mother is joking
今でも母が冗談を言っていると思う
Sorry for the recording today
今日は録画ですみません
I speak well
私はよく話します
Come
来て
So our first wave of spouse surveys
そこで配偶者調査の第一弾
After the decision in 2012, we will implement it in 2013
2012年決定後、2013年施行予定
Then from the second wave, we will implement it in the second year
そして第2波からは2年目に実施します
The third wave of investigations was completed last year.
第3波の捜査は昨年完了した。
So let's put it simply
では、簡単に言ってみましょう
if you forget later
後で忘れてしまったら
7% here are married
ここでは7%が既婚者
Average age 25
平均年齢25歳
19% to 20% here are married
ここでは19％から20％が既婚者です
Average age 28
平均年齢28歳
In this third wave of surveys, there are more than 39%
この第 3 波の調査では、39% 以上が
almost 40
ほぼ40
This is consistent with our government statistics
これは政府統計と一致しています
so we are happy
だから私たちは幸せです
I won't talk about this
これについては話しません
we have some topics that are different
異なるトピックがいくつかあります
Simply put, what I just said
簡単に言えば、今私が言ったこと
Now probably won't be able to make it to 40
おそらく40までは無理だろう
if not
そうでない場合
40-year-old parents and 40-year-old teenagers
40歳の両親と40歳の若者
the whole vertical metaphor
垂直方向の比喩全体
that is really necessary
それは本当に必要です
amazing thing
すごいこと
I hope some of our colleagues here are willing to take the list
ここにいる私たちの同僚の何人かがこのリストに参加してくれることを願っています
hehehehe
へへへへ
good
良い
Collect the whole data and look
全体のデータを集めて見てみる
wow, really powerful
うわー、本当に強力です
Probably all that I just reported to you
おそらく私があなたに報告したすべてのことです
It's all on this list
すべてこのリストに載っています
I take it apart
分解してみます
first stage
最初の段階
You can see that I put the net reverse rate
ネットリバースレートを入れているのがわかります
write on it
その上に書きます
Everyone should know that when they were in middle school
中学生の頃には誰もが知っていたはず
We are ballpoint pens, aren't we?
私たちはボールペンですよね。
Because our funds have always been consolidated
私たちの資金は常に統合されているため、
I'm sorry, at that time, it was really fundraising.
申し訳ありませんが、当時は本当に募金活動でした。
Later, after funding
その後、資金調達後、
We also give two hundred Taiwan dollars
私たちも200台湾ドルを差し上げます
what about the money
お金はどうですか
I found the West and exchanged it for US dollars
西を見つけて米ドルに交換した
I'm a little embarrassed
ちょっと恥ずかしいです
But I don't think it's okay
でも大丈夫だとは思わない
this meaningful thing
この意味のあること
Doesn't necessarily require a lot of resources
必ずしも多くのリソースを必要とするわけではない
we just try to do it
私たちはただそれをしようとしているだけです
so so probably
そうそう、おそらく
The second stage can be seen
第二段階が見える
we started
私たちは始めました
All are from the original more than 5,000
すべてオリジナルから5,000以上
but remember
でも覚えておいて
It was already the tenth wave and the eleventh wave.
もう第10波、第11波でした。
when the past nine waves
過去9回の波のとき
many people don't answer
多くの人は答えません
he just jumps
彼はただジャンプするだけです
Jumped out, I just talked about 60 or so, some 30 or so jumped out
飛び出してきた、さっき60人くらい話したけど、30人くらい飛び出してきた
We still try our best to ask these people
私たちは今でも、こうした人々に尋ねるように最善を尽くしています。
If the visitor says you have to knock on the door three times, it will be counted.
訪問者がドアを3回ノックする必要があると言うと、カウントされます。
No, so this stressful time is too much for the interviewer
いいえ、だからこのストレスの多い時期は面接官にとっては多すぎるのです
Every time we do a survey, we get some
アンケートを行うたびに、いくつかの情報が得られます
complaint letter
苦情の手紙
i mean please
つまりお願いします
I'm not good at English, when did you want to talk like this?
私は英語が苦手ですが、いつからこんな話をしたいと思いましたか？
We used to ask Mr. Zhang Honghua
私たちは張紅華氏によく尋ねました。
The reply letter of the eight tails of the video, in fact, let’s talk about it
ビデオの八尾の返信文 実はそれについて話しましょう
Just a word, we do academic research, we will continue to come
一言だけ、私たちは学術研究を行っています、これからも続けます
On the contrary, let me dismiss your intention
逆にあなたの意図は無視させてください
Later, after discussion, everyone said that this thing is not very fair to visitors.
その後、議論した結果、これは訪問者にとってあまり公平ではないと全員が言いました。
So we put those that are no longer there
だから私たちはもうそこにないものを置きます
And it has already clearly stated the people he interviewed in the drama
そして、ドラマの中でインタビューした人々についてはすでに明記されています
After removing him, we'll do it all over again
彼を削除した後、もう一度やり直します
Then you can see that the second wave has better results
そうすれば、第 2 波の方が良い結果が得られることがわかります。
Then the third wave had better results
その後、第 3 波の方が良い結果が得られました
During the same time period, we conduct interviews
同じ時間帯に面接も実施します
keep track, the original
オリジナルを追跡してください
Fifty one, sixty, keep chasing, chasing until now
51、60、追い続けて、追い続けて、今まで
Seventeen are still in there and no one else
17人がまだそこにいて、他には誰もいません
we don't want to
私たちはしたくない
And partly because
そして部分的には
The focus of our interview has changed slightly
インタビューの焦点が少し変わりました
i will say
私は言います
So simply say for example
たとえば単純に言ってみましょう
Qualitative research has 22
定性的調査には 22
i want to thank you very much
とても感謝したいです
I don't know how many of you
何人いるか分かりませんが、
We have visited four waves
私たちは4つの波を訪れました
The third and fourth waves begin
第3波、第4波が始まる
We don't have to go to Yilan
宜蘭に行く必要はありません
They came to us on a motorcycle
彼らはバイクで私たちのところに来ました
This is really different
これは本当に違います
But I really went to Yilan
でも本当に宜蘭に行ったんです
i still remember our assistant
私たちのアシスタントを今でも覚えています
When I go to Yilan to visit
宜蘭に遊びに行ったとき
the next car
次の車
i saw him lick ken
彼がケンを舐めているのを見た
I just remember that man's house was there
あの男の家がそこにあったのを覚えている
He said teacher how do you know
彼は「先生、どうして知っているの？」と言いました。
I say because of the interviewee
インタビュー対象者のせいで言う
let me dove twice
2回潜らせてください
so i know exactly where his house is
だから私は彼の家がどこにあるのか正確に知っています
things like this
このようなもの
just look at him
ただ彼を見てください
in the same class
同じクラスに
children in class together
一緒にクラスにいる子供たち
now some will be in
今、何人かが参加するでしょう
fishing port to visit him
彼を訪ねるための漁港
Some cook clear soup in the west
西部ではすまし汁を作る人もいる
Some dads call and say
電話してこう言うお父さんもいます
He is studying abroad for a Ph.D.
彼は博士号取得のために留学中です。
come back later
後で戻ってきます
this is what we talk about
これが私たちが話していることです
Multiple Growth Trajectories
複数の成長軌道
in my heart
この胸に
Feeling
フィーリング
Then we will continue to visit in the future
それでは、今後も訪問させていただきます
Simply put, we want to visit 20 unmarried
簡単に言うと、20人の未婚者を訪問したいのです
40 married
40 既婚
In this regard, we also ask Dr. Yuan Yongzhen for help.
この点に関しては、袁永振博士にも協力をお願いしています。
Then enter today's topic
それでは今日のトピックに入ります
pretty much what i said
ほぼ私が言ったこと
I also want to talk about the front for half an hour
30分くらいフロントの話もしたいです
I'm going to talk about the long-term effects of family experience.
家族の経験が長期的に及ぼす影響についてお話します。
Long-term effects of educational diversion and educational achievement
教育の転向と教育成績の長期的な影響
and the marriage and childbearing of the current young generation
そして今の若い世代の結婚・出産。
Our topic is called Zhuan Daren
私たちのタイトルはZhuan Darenです
So I must tell you what it means to become an adult.
だから、大人になるとはどういうことかを教えてあげなければなりません。
So I added it this morning
なので今朝追加しました
If you transfer to an adult, it is usually in academic research
社会人に転勤する場合は学術研究に就くことが多い
oldest this this this this
最も古い、これ、これ、これ
Usage This is Professor Shi Dalin Ruping
使用法 こちらはShi Dalin Ruping教授です
He finished an article he gave us later
彼は私たちに渡した記事を後で完成させました
Probably finish school and find a job
おそらく学校を卒業して仕事を見つけるでしょう
Get married, have a family, have children, etc.
結婚し、家族を持ち、子供が生まれるなど。
But Zhuan adults are one
しかし、ジュアンの大人は一つです
objective
目的
or subjective determination
または主観的な判断
did you say
言いましたか
When you are eighteen, you will be an adult
18歳になったら大人になるよ
you become an adult
あなたは大人になります
what about things like this
このようなことはどうですか
what about now
今はどう
There are some called big three
ビッグ3と呼ばれるものもある
you are responsible
あなたに責任があります
make your own decisions
自分で決断を下す
economically independent
経済的に自立している
to be honest
実を言うと
This is the same as the old indicator
これは古いインジケーターと同じです
that is more difficult to measure
それは測定するのがより困難です
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
what do you mean by making your own decision
自分で決めるとはどういう意味ですか
own responsibility
自己負責任
This is relatively simple
これは比較的簡単です
But everyone thinks this is not enough
しかし、誰もがこれでは十分ではないと考えています
because they think this thing
彼らはこんなことを考えているから
is a subjective determination
主観的な判断です
He needs some objective indicators
彼には客観的な指標が必要だ
to match him
彼に合わせるために
so we just
だから私たちはただ
use this scale
このスケールを使用してください
Then we made a scale
それからスケールを作りました
This scale is mainly based on Western
このスケールは主に西洋に基づいています
The adult scale they made
彼らが作った大人のスケール
But we will also cooperate
でも私たちも協力します
Our own Taiwan special
当店独自の台湾スペシャル
social context
社会的状況
For example, wind foster parents to parents before
たとえば、風が両親を両親に育てました。
This is probably the West
ここはおそらく西洋です
there will be no such topic
そんな話題もないだろう
Then the result
それでは結果は
The discovery can be divided into two major
この発見は大きく2つに分けられる
One is a mature personality
一つは大人びた性格
Will you wait for others
他の人を待ちますか
One is social role transformation
一つは社会的役割の変革
It is more like the traditional one just mentioned earlier.
これは、先ほど述べた従来のものに似ています。
As a result you can see
その結果、見ることができます
What men and women say
男と女の言うこと
Personality Maturity Vs Social Transformation
人格の成熟と社会の変革
more recognized
より認識される
it has a higher score
それはより高いスコアを持っています
Is there more than 4 o'clock and more than 3 o'clock?
4時以上と3時以上はありますか？
Then
それから
This indicator is also the same as that of Western studies
この指標も欧米の研究と同じです
Interestingly, males are more
興味深いことに、男性のほうが多いのです
Greater recognition of the norms of social norms
社会規範の規範に対する認識の向上
simply speaking
簡単に言えば
from the 1970s
1970年代から
research on attitudes towards gender roles
性別役割に対する態度に関する研究
There are two results that have not changed until now
今までと変わらない結果が2つあります
And it's the same all over the world
そしてそれは世界中どこでも同じです
First, men are more conservative than women
まず、男性は女性よりも保守的です
more traditional
より伝統的な
The second highly educated
2人目は高学歴
less educated than
～よりも教育が低い
less conservative
保守的ではない
probably these two
おそらくこの二人
whatever you do it won't change
何をしても変わらない
We study in Taiwan
私たちは台湾に留学します
There are three unfilial
不親心が３つある
After Empress Wu was great, she must give birth
武皇后は素晴らしかったので、彼女は出産しなければなりません
son's study also vent so
息子の勉強も兼ねているので
And after the fertility rate drops
そして出生率が下がった後は
This is even more so
これはさらにそうです
Originally, with the development of society
もともと、社会の発展に伴い、
This concept should go all the way down
このコンセプトは徹底的に徹底する必要があります
But when we were in 2008
しかし、2008 年の時点では
when you have a problem
問題があるとき
it rises immediately
それはすぐに上がります
So the general public
だから一般人は
the answer is quite rational
答えは非常に合理的です
We really want to trust everyone's answers
私たちは皆さんの回答を本当に信じたいと思っています
good
良い
Then the long-term impact of family structure
次に、家族構成の長期的な影響
There are many teachers in our group
私たちのグループにはたくさんの先生がいます
Including Mr. Zhong Yuhui present here, etc.
ここに出席している鍾裕輝氏なども含めて。
are here for a long time
長い間ここにいます
I think I'll tell you something here
ここで何かお伝えしようかと思います
family experiences we care about
私たちが大切にしている家族の経験
a structure a relationship
構造、関係
what is its long-term effect
その長期的な影響は何ですか
Then because I'm on the summary
それから、私は概要に載っているので、
There is a special mention of parental divorce
両親の離婚について特別に言及されている
What is the impact on the children
子どもたちにどんな影響があるのか
Then I will give you a report here
それではここでご報告させていただきます
Let's use a sample from this country to see
この国のサンプルを使って見てみましょう
In 2000, the first year of the National
2000 年の建国初年度
both his parents
彼の両親は両方とも
No divorce is 87
離婚なしは87歳
At the age of 22, it changed to 83.5
22歳では83.5歳に変化
At the age of 31, change
31歳で変わる
75.2 Why?
75.2 なぜ?
This is a divorce or separation
これは離婚か別居です
did you see
あなたは見ましたか
increase 0.5 0.5
増加 0.5 0.5
probably not that much
おそらくそれほど多くはありません
but one of the parents died
しかし両親のどちらかが亡くなった
increased a lot
たくさん増えた
So among today's 31-year-old adults
つまり、今日の31歳の大人の間では
we will see
様子を見よう
about a quarter
約4分の1
Not all parents are together
保護者全員が集まるわけではありません
So the family structure changes
それで家族構成が変わる
if you want to do research
研究したいなら
You are divided into two-parent families and non-two-parent families
二人親家庭と非二人親家庭に分かれる
about what i said
私が言ったことについて
about three quarters
4分の3くらい
This thing is most related to blunt
これがブラントに最も関係することです
you can see
見ることができます
College Graduation for Two-Parent Families
二人親家庭の大学卒業
The ratio is relatively high, right?
比率は比較的高いですよね？
Those who graduated from high school in non-parental families
両親以外の家庭で高校を卒業した方
relatively high ratio
比較的高い比率
So there are some differences in education level
教育レベルに多少の違いはありますが、
then i will talk next
それでは次に話します
I start from the family structure and family relationship
家族構成から始める 家族関係
Impact on Adolescents' Journeys
青少年の旅への影響
I'll jump off us first
まず私たちから飛び降ります
PYP shows you how our population structure has changed
PYP は人口構造がどのように変化したかを示します
The problem of declining birthrate and aging population
少子高齢化問題
And then from the parental divorce what we call the incomplete family upbringing
そして、両親の離婚から、いわゆる不完全な家庭教育が始まります。
To observe the development of intimate relationships and family formation in adulthood
成人期における親密な関係の発展と家族形成を観察する
this piece
この作品
This is the number of children born
これは生まれた子供の数です
You can see that in 1976 we had 420,000 births in Taiwan
1976 年に台湾では 42 万人が出生したことがわかります。
The lowest time was only 160,000
最低の時はわずか16万だった
180,000 were born last year
そして昨年の出生数は18万人でした
So our fertility rate is declining very fast
つまり出生率は非常に急速に低下している
The red ones tell you that this is the fertility rate
赤い部分は出生率を示しています
down like this
このように下がって
then why
それでなんで
you can see
見ることができます
As long as it is a farming year, the fertility rate must increase
農耕年である限り出生率は上がらなければならない
All the way down, there will be a high wind in the agricultural year
農耕期にはずっと強風が吹くだろう
This is how I see cultural norms from this graph
このグラフから文化的規範がどのように見えるか
This thing that never dies
決して死なないこのもの
That
それか
Taiwan is very important
台湾はとても重要です
Do you see the lonely year
孤独な一年が見えますか
Marriage rate dropped from 6.5 to 5
結婚率は6.5から5に低下
don't get married
不要結婚
Year of the Tiger
寅年
That's when our Taiwan had the lowest birth rate in the world
それは私たちの台湾の出生率が世界で最も低かったときです
Because people don't want to have children
みんな子供を産みたくないから
the government is very worried
政府は非常に心配している
Fortunately, the next year is the 100th year of the Republic of China, advertising everywhere
幸いなことに、来年は中華民国100周年であり、あちこちで広告が行われています。
Originally a hundred years and what a hundred years
本来は百年、なんと百年。
A hundred years of harmony is not enough
百年の調和では足りない
The second year is the Year of the Dragon
2年目は辰年です
that all the parents are trying to do
親全員がやろうとしていること
if the children have a spouse
子供に配偶者がいる場合
get married quickly
早く結婚してください
I just hope to give birth to a dragon son or a dragon girl.
ドラゴンの息子かドラゴンの女の子が生まれることを願うばかりです。
you can see
見ることができます
Year of the Dragon jumps so high in the second year
辰年は2年目で急上昇
But now it's slowly falling
でも今はゆっくりと下がってきている
if you look at this
これを見たら
you can see the divorce rate
離婚率がわかる
It's probably leveled off.
おそらく平らになっていると思います。
So the marriage rate goes up and down
だから結婚率は上がったり下がったりするんだよ
Only a hundred years of happiness and birth
幸福と誕生は百年だけ
then came down again
それからまた降りてきた
but this
しかしこれは
As long as it is the Year of the Tiger
寅年である限り
as long as it is the year of the dragon
辰年である限り
Must be born
一定生
So you're in a downward spiral
つまり、あなたは負のスパイラルに陥っているのです
When you meet the Year of the Dragon, give birth
辰年を迎えたら産めよ
we are in such a society
私たちはそのような社会にいます
I just want to share with you
ただあなたと共有したいだけです
The influence of cultural norms
文化的規範の影響
sometimes you don't even have to ask
尋ねる必要すらない場合もあります
agree or disagree he is here
同意するか同意しない、彼はここにいる
he is like this
彼はこんな感じです
So in terms of unmarried men and women in Taiwan
台湾の未婚男女に関して言えば、
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
Of course, the unmarried rate of women is high
もちろん女性の未婚率も高い
But it's quite high
でもかなり高いですよ
So back to our own research
私たち自身の研究に戻りましょう
Let's talk about whether the family structure has any influence
家族構成が影響するかどうかについて話しましょう
we know low birth rates
私たちは出生率が低いことを知っています
this problem is serious
この問題は深刻です
And the phenomenon of marriage metaphor package
そして結婚メタファーパッケージの現象
It means that the society still does not accept out-of-wedlock children
それは社会がまだ婚外子を受け入れていないことを意味します
I remember when I was doing an interview
インタビューしていたときのことを思い出します
He said that the unmarried pregnant interviewee
彼は、未婚の妊娠中のインタビュー対象者が、
Tell me he doesn't even want to marry him
彼は結婚したくないと言ってくれ
Because he thinks he can't get along with him and doesn't love each other
なぜなら彼は自分とはうまくやっていけない、お互いを愛していないと思っているからです。
Parents say I don't care if you love each other or not
両親は、あなたがお互いを愛しているかどうかは気にしないと言います
you hurry to get married
あなたは結婚を急ぐ
divorce after childbirth
出産後に離婚
Then I think hey, yes
そうしたら、ああ、そうだと思います
This is the wedding package we've been talking about
これが私たちが話していたウェディングパッケージです
child to be born in marriage
結婚して生まれる子供
this is very important
これはとても重要です
so what
だから何
Why Young People Lack Motivation to Marry and Have Children
なぜ若者は結婚や出産への意欲を失ってしまうのか
this is what everyone is asking
これは誰もが求めていることです
Let's start with family experience
家族体験から始めましょう
In particular our data allow us to explore from early experience
特に私たちのデータにより、初期の経験から調査することができます
then speaking
それから話す
Early Family Experiences for Adolescents
青少年のための初期の家族体験
Regardless of childhood and adolescence
幼少期・青年期問わず
Are the parents divorced?
両親は離婚していますか？
In many Chinese families, the parents do not divorce
中国の多くの家庭では両親は離婚しない
but conflicting
しかし矛盾している
complete family
完全な家族
We also call it a complete family here.
ここではそれを完全な家族とも呼びます。
But what if we add a disguise?
しかし、変装を加えたらどうなるでしょうか？
parent-child conflict
親子の対立
Early experiences of adolescence
思春期の初期の経験
Dating Behavior in Your Early Adulthood
成人初期のデート行動
what are the marriage expectations
結婚の期待は何ですか
especially in your 30s
特に30代は
We can talk about the actual act of marriage
結婚という実際の行為について話すことができます
Everyone here should know
ここにいる誰もが知っているはずです
Because newspapers and magazines often say
新聞や雑誌でよく言われるので、
The average age of marriage in Taiwan
台湾の平均結婚年齢
Probably male 32 years old
たぶん32歳の男の子
30 years old girl
30歳の女の子
So we also say that our data is just right
したがって、私たちのデータは正しいとも言えます
react to such a situation
そのような状況に反応する
I can only speak quickly
早口でしか話せません
Generally speaking, the situation of children under divorced parents will tell you
一般的に、離婚した両親の下にある子供の状況は次のとおりです。
His self-esteem comes first
他自尊第一
bad grades wait
悪い成績は待ってください
negative impact
マイナスの影響
And often tell you it will last into adulthood
そしてそれは大人になっても続くだろうとよく言います
However, it is uncertain in the literature that
ただし、文献上では不明です。
After parents divorce, children are less likely to want to marry
親が離婚すると子供は結婚したがらなくなる
Or get married early
それとも早く結婚するか
Because if a child doesn't want to marry it's because he sees conflict
なぜなら、子供が結婚したくないのは、彼が不和を感じているからです。
Seeing that the parent-child relationship is not good
親子関係がうまくいっていないことがわかる
But some marry early because he thinks he needs a
しかし、結婚が必要だと考えて早く結婚する人もいます。
relation
関係
He comes from a place where resources are relatively scarce
彼は資源が比較的不足している場所の出身です
He needs to get into marriage
彼は結婚する必要がある
So this is the one we want to know
これが私たちが知りたいことです
The topic of the research is as follows
研究テーマは以下の通りです
so what
だから何
We climb points complete family divorced family
私たちは完全な家族を目指します 離婚した家族
We pay special attention to this divorced family
私たちはこの離婚した家族に特別な注意を払っています
when he got divorced
彼が離婚したとき
Before 13 or 12
13時か12時前
12, Stan's Upper or Under 12
12、スタンのアッパーまたはアンダー12
Then full family, we join a cumulative conflict
それから家族全員で、私たちは累積的な紛争に加わります
go see the difference
違いを見に行ってください
We want the explanation to be him
彼に説明してもらいたい
Dating Behavior in Early Adulthood, Late Adolescence and His Marriage Expectations
成人期初期、青年期後期のデート行動と彼の結婚への期待
That's when you're 19 to 20 years old
それは19歳から20歳の頃です
simply speaking
簡単に言えば
As you can see, let's say it's a two-parent family
ご覧のとおり、両親がいる家庭だとします。
Probably this ratio
たぶんこの比率
But my parents divorced when I was in elementary school
しかし、両親は私が子供の頃に離婚しました
How is he, compared to 13 years old
13歳と比べて彼はどうですか？
After the age of 13, the parents experience the divorce of their parents
13歳以降に両親の離婚を経験
He has relatively no marriage expectations, he won't say he wants to get married
彼は結婚願望があまりなく、結婚したいとは言いません。
But before the age of 12, there are more dating partners
しかし、12歳になるまでは、より多くのデートパートナーがいます
and the number of people who are dating
そして付き合っている人の数
He is more interested in the development of intimacy, so let's talk about it
彼は親密さの発展にもっと興味があるので、それについて話しましょう
What about parental conflict?
親の不和についてはどうでしょうか？
He acted like the one whose parents divorced after the age of 13
彼は13歳の後に両親が離婚した人のような振る舞いをした
that that category
そのカテゴリーが
So in addition, we also found in this study
さらに、この研究でわかったことは、
It can be seen that the sense of attachment between parents and children is very important
親と子の愛着感がとても大切であることがわかります。
If you compare your relationship with your father
父親との関係を比べてみると
good words you are less likely to say
あなたが言う可能性が低い良い言葉
we have marriage expectations
私たちは結婚の期待を持っています
Divorce if your child wife and parents
子供の妻と両親の場合は離婚してください
But if you have a good relationship with your mother
でも、母親との関係が良好であれば、
You also have less expectation of marriage
結婚への期待も薄れてしまう
In other words, everyone can hear
つまり誰でも聞こえる
Divorce or not is a family structure
離婚するかどうかは家族構成による
But you are in a divorced family structure
でもあなたは離婚した家族構成です
relationship with parents family relationship
両親との関係 家族関係
can have some harmonizing effect
ある程度の調和効果が得られる
like this
このような
So if you're with a two-parent family
つまり、両親がいる家族の場合は、
And the group with low conflict
そして対立が少ないグループ
Parents' Early Divorce Experience
両親の早期離婚経験
lead to young adulthood
若年成人につながる
Negative effects of intimacy
親密さの悪影響
So sometimes I have been busy for a year and a half
それで時々私は1年半忙しかったです
Everyone just got this sentence
誰もがこの文を受け取りました
Everyone listened in one go
全員が一気に聞きました
well then
じゃあ
adult children
大人の子供
We found from 201114
201114から見つけました
It's strange, parents can't get divorced
不思議だよ、親は離婚できないんだよ
It has little to do with his actual marriage
彼の実際の結婚とはほとんど関係がありません
Definitely a two-parent family
間違いなく二人親家庭です
Grown children are less likely to seek marriage
成長した子供は結婚を求める可能性が低い
probably so
おそらくそうだろう
so we say what to do
それで私たちは何をすべきかを言います
Okay, let's guess step by step. Don't worry.
さて、段階的に推測しましょう。心配しないでください。
Let's first invite Professor Dai Cuier from Taipei University
まずは台北大学のダイ・クイエ教授をお招きしましょう
For the 7% of 25-year-olds who were married in 2011
2011 年に結婚した 25 歳の 7% にとって
let's see what's going on
何が起こっているのか見てみましょう
literature tells us
文学が教えてくれる
Families High in Conflict Have Lower Marriage Expectations
対立が多い家族は結婚への期待が低い
Does that mean you're less likely to seek marriage when you're 25?
ということは、25歳になると結婚する可能性は低くなるということでしょうか？
Well, after he made various arrangements,
さて、いろいろと手配をした結果、
I'll show you first
まずはお見せします
we are probably like this now
私たちはきっと今こうなっている
These married people we DIP married people
これらの既婚者たち、私たちは既婚者たちをDIPします
This is probably the case
おそらくこれが事実です
He has fathered children quite tall
彼はかなり背の高い子供たちを育てた
In other words, marriage and childbirth are a package
つまり、結婚と出産はセットなのです
He's getting married, he's really going to have kids
彼は結婚する予定で、本当に子供が生まれる予定だ
but give birth within seven months of marriage
ただし結婚後7ヶ月以内に出産する
I do not include those born before marriage
結婚前に生まれた人は含まない
So this pre-marriage
それでこの結婚前
For example this is 52%
たとえば、これは 52% です
at the age of 25
25歳のとき
What is it called?
それはなんと呼ばれていますか？
In fact, not only 52%
実際、52% だけではありません。
Because 89% of you are already born
なぜなら、あなた方の89%はすでに生まれているからです。
you can say it like this
このように言えます
Then we also ask by the way
それからついでに聞いてみます
But when you're 28 or 31, it's more normal, right?
でも、28歳や31歳になると、もっと普通になりますよね？
Then you can see
そうすればわかります
contemporary young couple
現代的な若いカップル
These are all under 32
これらは全員32歳未満です
The average ratio of living with parents is quite high
親との同居率は平均的にかなり高い
This is of course related to economic resources
もちろんこれは経済資源に関係します
This is absolutely different from European and American countries.
ここが欧米諸国とは全く違うところです。
Taiwan is in the middle of East Asia
台湾は東アジアの真ん中にあります
It has always been relatively similar to the Korean model.
それは常に韓国のモデルに比較的似ています。
But I don't know if they have such information
しかし、彼らがそのような情報を持っているかどうかはわかりません
then you can see
そうすればわかります
On one side of the island, the husband and the parents are the main ones
島の片方では夫と両親がメイン
There will be no fewer than Qifang's parents
チーファンの両親も少なくないでしょう
good
良い
Professor Dai Xuwei and others
戴徐維教授等
He said I'd first look at pregnancy before marriage
彼は私が結婚する前にまず妊娠について考えるだろうと言いました
I found out my parents divorced when I was 13
13歳の時に両親が離婚したことを知った
more likely to lead to premarital pregnancy
婚前妊娠につながる可能性が高い
You have cohabitation and premarital sexual experience
同棲歴があり、婚前性交渉の経験がある
possible
可能
So what about early marriage, will you find out that your parents are divorced and gone?
では、早婚の場合はどうなるでしょうか。両親が離婚していないことを知ることになるでしょうか?
But this thing came out
でもこんなものが出てきました
In other words, this is called the family structure
つまり、これを家族構成といいます。
this is called family relationship
これを家族関係という
And in this relationship, parent-child conflict is high
そして、この関係では親子の対立が多くなります
He is more likely to marry early
彼は早く結婚する可能性が高い
But seeing the conflict between parents
しかし、両親の対立を見ていると、
Less likely to get married but not to marry early
結婚する可能性は低いが、早期に結婚することはない
So in adolescence, it's very similar to what I just said earlier.
つまり、思春期では、先ほど言ったことと非常によく似ています。
Adolescent Witnessing Parents Arguing
両親が口論しているのを目撃した思春期の子供たち
and divorced parents will reduce his desire to marry
そして両親が離婚すると結婚願望が薄れるだろう
But if there is a conflict between parents and children
しかし、親と子の間で不和が生じた場合、
Instead he hurried to get married
その代わりに彼は結婚を急いだ
So in this study
そこでこの研究では
If parents divorced before the age of 13
両親が13歳未満で離婚した場合
Will affect pre-marital pregnancy of children
子供の結婚前の妊娠に影響を与える
But it won't affect your early marriage
でもそれはあなたの早期結婚には影響しません
Early adolescence, high parental conflict will not marry early
思春期初期、親との衝突が多い場合は早期に結婚しない
High parent-child conflict leads to early marriage, it's clear
親子対立が多いと早婚につながることは明らか
But those with cohabitation and premarital relationships are also more likely to marry early
しかし、同棲や婚前交渉を行っている人は、早期に結婚する可能性も高い
Is that clear?
それは明らかですか？
I'm very hardworking
私はとても勤勉です
To put it simply, there is a marriage package phenomenon
簡単に言えば、結婚パッケージ現象があります
You said that between cultural norms and economic change
あなたは文化的規範と経済的変化の間にあると言いました
This level of tension is a characteristic of Chinese society
このレベルの緊張は中国社会の特徴です
The parcels of the marriage between generations are all in this place
世代間同棲結婚の荷物はすべてここにある
However, Western studies often talk about an economic capacity
しかし、西洋の研究では経済力についてよく議論されています。
something that affects you a lot that we're just going to observe
あなたに大きな影響を与えるもので、私たちはただ観察するだけです
But economic ability, they found that it is beneficial to men
しかし、経済能力は男性にとって有利であることがわかりました
The effect of living in different places has contributed
異なる場所に住んでいることの影響
Contribute to him to get married, but it is the opposite for girls
彼の結婚に貢献しますが、女の子は逆です
Girls who have high financial ability are less likely to think that they are married
経済力の高い女子は結婚していると考える可能性が低い
hope and desire
希望と願望
so so we say ok , let's look at 28 years old
それで、わかりました、28 歳を見てみましょう
during the second wave
第二波の最中に
What's the problem, 25 years old
何が問題なの、25歳
I think if you call him an early marriage, no one will have a problem
彼を早婚と言えば誰も問題ないと思う
Because he obeyed his son's order to get married, that's why
息子の結婚命令に従ったのもそれが理由だ
Well, at the age of 28, just now he is slowly approaching normal
まあ、28歳になった今、彼は徐々に普通に近づきつつある
So Ma Guoxun
宋馬国善
Professor Ma Guoxun, I am asking this question
馬国善先生、私はこの質問をしています。
I think what's the reason you got married and got out of prison?
結婚して刑務所から出所した理由は何だと思いますか？
is there any difference
違いはありますか
I'll go faster here
ここではもっと早く行きます
I just let everyone know we're not kidding
冗談ではないことをみんなに伝えておきます
we really take it seriously
私たちはそれを本当に真剣に受け止めています
Especially our Vice President Huang
特に黄副社長
is our funding
私たちの資金です
we need to tell him
私たちは彼に伝える必要があります
look at
見る
there is a recording for today
今日の録音があります
this structural factor
この構造的要因
Normative factors
規範的要因
relational factors
関係要因
I just said that structure is a resource
先ほど構造はリソースだと言いました
relationship is also a resource
人間関係も資源です
This is the big trend
これが大きなトレンドです
it's interpersonal
それは対人関係です
The other is cultural norms
もう一つは文化的規範です
Then generally do it, of course it depends on whether you are learning
それから、通常はそれを実行します。もちろん、学習しているかどうかによって異なります。
Is there a job?
仕事はありますか？
fine human ability
素晴らしい人間能力
Then we use the survey of the main book
次に、メインブックのアンケートを使用します。
All the way from 16 years old to 20 to 30 years old
16歳から20歳、30歳まで
Then use the first two waves of spouse surveys
その後、配偶者調査の最初の 2 つのウェーブを使用します。
Then use this model to do
次に、このモデルを使用して次のことを行います
What we're trying to explain is the age of marriage
私たちが説明しようとしているのは結婚年齢です
with the age of release from prison
刑務所から釈放される年齢に合わせて
analysis in disguise
変装した分析
e.g. structural disguise
例：構造上の偽装
we used where are you
私たちはどこにいるのを使いました
Parents' Education Achievement Family Income
両親の学歴 世帯収入
relatively large
比較巨式的
normative attitude
規範的な態度
gender role attitudes
性別役割に対する態度
what traditional family values
伝統的な家族が大切にしているもの
in terms of family relations
家族関係の面で
We used negative parent-child conflict
否定的な親子対立を使用しました
positive family ties
ポジティブな家族の絆
These are the constitution
これらが憲法です
Then we add another question
次に、別の質問を追加します
when i was fifteen
私が15歳のとき
Whether the parents are divorced or separated
両親が離婚または別居しているかどうか
Because I just used twelve
ちょうど12個使ったから
then thirteen to sixteen
それから13歳から16歳まで
Then I'll see if you're fifteen to cut the root
じゃあ、君が15歳になったら根を絶つかどうか見てみるよ
what's the difference
違いは何ですか
This is an academic research to try
これは試みるべき学術研究です
Then this is all there
それからこれですべてです
we all do it
私たちは皆それをします
I just take this example
この例を挙げてみます
Let's see marriage first
まずは結婚を見てみましょう
You will see the marriage rate in Yilan
宜蘭の結婚率がわかります
taller than them
彼らよりも背が高い
less educated parents
教育水準の低い親
more likely to find marriage
結婚できる可能性が高くなります
But in terms of family income
しかし、世帯収入で考えると
Male household income and financial status
男性の世帯収入と経済状況
more abundant
より豊富な
He is more likely to marry
彼は結婚する可能性が高い
no effect on women
女性には影響なし
look at this get out of prison
これを見て刑務所から出てください
It seems to be the same as the complete copy
完全コピーと同じっぽい
But here women come out
しかしここで女性が出てくる
didn't it matter just now?
今は関係なかったですか？
The female family gave back
女性家族がお返しした
less abundant more likely
量が少ないほど可能性が高い
Giving birth, this place is different
出産、ここは違う
Let's use this method to explain one by one
この方法を使って一つずつ説明していきましょう
You look like first marriage too
あなたも初婚のようですね
Men with good family relationships will marry early
家族関係が良好な男性は結婚が早い
no effect on women
女性には影響なし
However, when the age of 15, the parents were divorced or separated.
しかし、15歳のとき、両親は離婚または別居。
It has no effect on men, but on women it will lead to early marriage
男性には影響がありませんが、女性には早期結婚につながります。
clear gender difference
明らかな性差
I am consistent with many documents
多くの文書と一致しています
Early Childhood is the same
幼児期も同じ
You see, if the family relationship is good, men will give birth early
ほら、家族関係が良ければ男性は早く出産するんだよ
Parents divorce, women will have early childbearing
両親が離婚すると女性は早く出産することになる
no effect on other
他には影響なし
we sit all the way
私たちはずっと座っています
Conclusions are structural, relational and normative factors
結論は構造的、関係的、規範的な要素です
will affect the marriage and childbearing of Taiwan's younger generation
台湾の若い世代の結婚と出産に影響を与えるだろう
For researchers
研究者向け
Some important disguises you will come into contact with when studying architecture
建築を勉強するときに遭遇する重要な変装
Such a result
このような結果
psychologically happy
心理的に幸せ
then on the other hand
それから一方では
Importantly, the effect of gender differences
重要なのは、性差の影響です。
very obvious
非常に明白な
for men
男性用
His family income was relatively high before he was a teenager
彼が10代になる前は彼の世帯収入は比較的高かった
good family relationship
良い家族関係
And he currently has a job
そして彼は現在仕事をしています
He is more likely to marry and have children before the age of 28
彼は28歳までに結婚して子供を産む可能性が高い
But for women
でも女性にとっては
If parents are divorced or separated
両親が離婚または別居している場合
He is more likely to marry and have children
彼は結婚して子供を産む可能性が高い
But when he was a teenager, his family income was high
しかし、彼が10代の頃、彼の世帯収入は高かった
he currently has a job
彼は現在仕事をしています
he is less likely to marry
他比較不可能結婚
less likely to have children
子供を産む可能性が低い
So this is the model that is equal to the income of the western economy
つまり、これは西側経済の所得に等しいモデルです
Get verified here
ここで認証を受ける
so in short
要するに
Have financial ability and early positive family life experience
経済的能力と初期の前向きな家庭生活経験がある
Powerful masculinity is negative for women
強力な男性性は女性にとってマイナスです
And if the parents divorce before the middle teens,
そして両親が10代半ばになる前に離婚した場合、
More likely to cause women's early marriage and early childbearing
女性の早婚と早産を引き起こす可能性が高い
That is, he may come from an environment that is less resource-advantaged
つまり、彼は資源にあまり恵まれていない環境の出身である可能性があります
he needs a relationship
彼には関係が必要だ
What about the next 31 years old?
次の31歳はどうなるでしょうか？
Every researcher has their own unique
研究者にはそれぞれ独自の特徴があります
research interest and the point of view he wants to explore
研究への関心と探求したい視点
So many interviewees said why they always have the same problem
非常に多くのインタビュー対象者が、なぜいつも同じ問題を抱えているのかを語った
Because every stage is different
ステージごとに違うから
The overall look will be different, right?
全体的な印象も変わってきますよね？
so let's look at this
それでこれを見てみましょう
What Professor Liu Jiahua of Tamkang said about our previous Post
前回の投稿について淡江大学のLiu Jiahua教授が語った内容
He made some long-term effects on the integrity of the family structure
彼は家族構成の健全性に長期的な影響を与えた
You want to see if there is a difference for gender
性別による違いがあるかどうかを確認したい
OK, let's combine the two sets of samples.
OK、2 セットのサンプルを結合しましょう。
The one just now was shown to you with a national art sample
さっき見せていただいたのは、国立美術品のサンプルです
Both groups look together
両方のグループが一緒に見えます
You can see that about 76.4 means that the parents are still there
約 76.4 は、両親がまだそこにいることを意味することがわかります。
No divorce, one parent is dead
離婚はしていない、片方の親は亡くなっている
Already 14% at an average age of 61
平均年齢61歳ですでに14％
Then the divorce rate is about 9.7, which is about 10%.
それから離婚率は約9.7、約10％になります。
Then the marital status of the parents
次に両親の婚姻状況
You said the two-parent marriage continued and the parents were divorced.
二人親の結婚生活が続いて両親が離婚したとおっしゃいました。
Percentage of married to one of the deceased parents
亡くなった両親の一方と結婚している割合
That's probably how marriage lasts up to
おそらく結婚生活はそうやって続くのでしょう
But the parents are divorced
でも両親は離婚してる
we break it down into so many stages
私たちはそれを非常に多くの段階に分割します
one is a baby wife
一人は赤ん坊の妻です
A primary school period, a teenage period, a college period, and an adult period
小学生時代、10代、大学生時代、そして大人時代
As you can see, ages 6 to 17 are significantly lower, very much
ご覧のとおり、6 歳から 17 歳は大幅に低く、非常に低いです。
Because the average parental divorce is 36, but only 31 in these two stages
なぜなら、親の離婚の平均は 36 歳ですが、この 2 つの段階ではわずか 31 歳だからです。
However, children whose parents divorced in childhood were most likely to marry
しかし、幼少期に両親が離婚した子供は結婚する可能性が最も高かった
It depends on whether there is any difference between men and women. These three are the ones I explained just now.
男性と女性で違いがあるかどうかによりますが、先ほど説明したのはこの3つです。
Since we are 6 to 12 and 13 to 17 are low, we have to combine them
6～12と13～17は低いので組み合わせないといけません。
You can see that among those whose parents are divorced, it affects men the most
両親が離婚している人の中で、最も影響を受けるのは男性であることがわかります。
If he has no parents in childhood, he is most likely to marry early, and he will marry like this
子供の頃に両親がいない場合、彼は早く結婚する可能性が最も高く、このように結婚するでしょう
It cannot be said that he married early, because he is 31 years old, but when he is at school age, he is the least likely to get married
彼は31歳なので結婚が早かったとは言えませんが、学生時代が最も結婚する可能性が低いです。
The same is true for women. After a woman reaches adulthood, her parents will divorce and she will rise again.
女性も同様で、女性は成人すると両親が離婚し、再び立ち上がることになります。
Some people say that it may be better to use a picture to represent this thing
これを表現するには絵を使った方が良いのではないかと言う人もいます
more obvious isn't it
もっと明白ですよね
For me I think the number is more obvious
私にとっては数字の方がわかりやすいと思います
but it's okay you see
でも大丈夫ですよ、わかります
When children are six to seven years old
子どもが6歳から7歳のとき
It's really unlikely to get married.
本当に結婚できる可能性は低いです。
This gray one is all
この灰色のものがすべてです
blue is male
青は男性です
red is rain
赤は雨です
Just look at the time from one to fifteen years old
1歳から15歳までを見てください
Boys are the most likely to marry, right?
結婚する可能性が最も高いのは男の子ですよね？
That woman's parents divorced during adulthood
その女性の両親は成人期に離婚した
He is also more likely to marry
彼は結婚する可能性も高い
Then come down again, what do you think?
それからまた降りてきて、どう思いますか？
you first than
あなたよりも先に
Is that a category just now?
それって今のカテゴリーですか？
did not look together
一緒に見なかった
you can't just say for sure
確かに言うことはできません
It's really bad to get a divorce.
離婚するのは本当にダメです。
worse than dead parents
死んだ両親よりも悪い
you don't know
あなたは知りません
because you watch it together
一緒に見るから
if you look at it together
一緒に見たら
you will find
見つけるだろう
One of the parents died is the least likely to marry
両親のどちらかが亡くなった場合、結婚する可能性が最も低い
He's more prominent than a divorce
彼は離婚よりも有名だ
So let's confirm this first
それではまずこれを確認しましょう
see you later
また後で
what about divorce
離婚はどうですか
I still divide these time points the same
私はまだこれらの時点を同じように分割します
Compared with the death of one of the parents
両親のどちらかが亡くなった場合と比べて
discovering that one of the parents has passed away
両親のどちらかが亡くなったことを発見
is a persistent and significant
永続的かつ重要です
at least for men
少なくとも男性にとっては
And at school age
そして学齢期には
if parents divorce
両親が離婚した場合
Significantly lower for men too
男性でも大幅に下がる
Not so serious for women
女性にとってはそれほど深刻ではありません
Is that clear?
それは明らかですか？
Then next this
じゃあ次はこれ
tell us what
何を教えてください
At least we are 31 years old
少なくとも私たちは31歳です
Adult children come to see
大人になった子供たちが見に来ます
you and family structure
あなたと家族構成
completely complete compared to
に比べて完全に完成
The death of a parent will reduce the
親が亡くなれば減額される
possibility of marriage
結婚の可能性
but the parents divorced
しかし両親は離婚した
did not achieve a significant effect
顕著な効果は得られなかった
it looks like you just
まるであなたのようです
Is the divorce you want to talk about gone?
あなたが話したい離婚はもう終わったのですか？
But this place is here
でもここはここだよ
so we see
それでわかります
sooner or later parents divorce
遅かれ早かれ両親は離婚する
Impact on children's likelihood of marriage
子どもの結婚の可能性に与える影響
son is Mr.
息子はMr.
The daughter was born first
娘が先に生まれた
right
右
right, right?
そうそう？
son is Mr.
息子はMr.
The daughter was born first
娘が先に生まれた
The third
第3
The point of divorce between parents is children
両親の離婚のポイントは子供
The greatest impact on men
男性への最大の影響
more dangerous for men
男性にとってはもっと危険
Okay, so just at this point we saw that one of the parents passed away.
さて、ちょうどこの時点で、両親の一人が亡くなったことがわかりました。
The same is true for men
男性も同様です
obvious impact
明らかな影響
So whether it's divorce or death
だから離婚でも死でも
The family structure has changed
家族構成が変わった
The marriage of the sons as adults
成人した息子たちの結婚
have a negative impact
マイナスの影響がある
So it's probably like this
だから多分こんな感じです
ok so to put it simply
わかりました、簡単に言えば
I just spent a little more time talking to you about the above
上記についてもう少し時間をかけてお話しました
Structural Relational Factors Long-Term Effects
構造的関係要因の長期的影響
Just take this early family experience of parental divorce
両親の離婚という初期の家族の経験を考えてみましょう
The conclusions of our current research can be condensed into these few sentences
私たちの現在の研究の結論は、次の数文に要約できます。
You can see the divorce of childhood parents
幼少期の両親の離婚がわかる
You're More Likely To Date You're Pregnant Before Marriage
結婚前に妊娠しているとデートする可能性が高くなります
but not early marriage
でも早婚ではない
But if the teenage parents divorce
しかし、10代の両親が離婚した場合、
you don't want to get married
あなたは結婚したくないのですか
but for women
しかし女性の場合
Instead, it increases his chances of early marriage and early childbearing
むしろ、早期に結婚し、早期に出産する可能性が高まります。
Parent-child conflict in the family relationship
家族関係における親子の対立
Often take care of the children and leave the family to get married
子供の世話をし、結婚のために家族を離れることが多い
but see
でも見てください
parental conflict not parent-child conflict
親子の対立ではなく、親の対立
He doesn't want to get married
彼は結婚したくない
He is also less likely to marry early
彼は早期に結婚する可能性も低い
That family cohesion is high
家族の結束力が高い
Family relationship plays a role in boys' early marriage and early childbearing
家族関係は少年の早期結婚と早期出産に影響を与える
So this is also an example
ということで、これも一例です
Said that the government wants people to get married and have children all the time
政府は人々が常に結婚して子供を産むことを望んでいると述べた
In fact, what should be tried is
実際に試してみるべきことは、
work hard on family education
家庭教育に熱心に取り組む
At least for men it is very noticeable effect
少なくとも男性にとっては非常に顕著な効果です
OK, then I'll move on to the second topic.
それでは、2 番目の議題に移ります。
It is our educational diversion
それは私たちの教育の転用です
Then this educational diversion
そして、この教育的流用
our many studies
私たちの多くの研究
I'm doing a little integration here
ここで少し統合を行っています
The first diversion was probably when we were in high school
最初に気をそらしたのはおそらく私たちが高校生の時でした
18 years old for the second diversion
2回目の転用は18歳
Then when the first average
その後、最初の平均が得られたとき、
you can see about half and half
半分くらい見えます
It is about half and half for those who study high value or junior college in high school
高校・高等・短大に進学する人は約半々です。
at the age of 18
18歳のとき
You can see that 74% of high school students went to colleges and universities
高校生の 74% が大学に進学していることがわかります。
But there are also 10% who take the exam
しかし、試験を受ける人も10％います
then in
それから
When I was a freshman and when I was a senior in high school, 14 was still there
私が1年生のときも高校3年生のときも、まだ14歳だった
I've already gone to work or to tutoring
もう仕事か家庭教師に行っています
As for the 50% of this
このうち50％に関しては、
What about the Higher Vocational Technology University, you can see it
高等職業技術大学はどうですか、わかります。
4.7% went to university
4.7%が大学に進学
Most are still in HKUST
大部分はまだ香港税関にいます
But the rate of work is of course very high
もちろん稼働率は非常に高いです
It is also conceivable
それも考えられる
Taiwan's education competition, this is
台湾の教育コンテスト、これが
I guess none of us would
私たちの誰もそうは思わないと思います
I won't doubt it, so I can skip it here
疑うつもりはないのでここでは飛ばしても大丈夫です
In particular, I think we've seen in research
特に、私たちが研究で見たことがあるのは、
Families and schools actually affect children's academic performance
家庭と学校は実際に子供の学力に影響を与える
is very consistent
非常に一貫しています
i most remember i used to say
私がよく言っていたのを一番覚えています
Because Professor Zhou Yuhui and Professor Huang Langman
なぜなら、周裕輝教授と黄朗満教授だからです。
Our colleagues have done
私たちの同僚がやったのは、
Quality of life of middle-aged parents
中年の親の生活の質
Of course parent-child relationship is very important
もちろん親子関係はとても大切です
a factor but
要因ですが、
I don't think the West will have this thing
西側諸国がこれを持っているとは思わない
Children's homework is good for mother's this
子どもの宿題はお母さんのこれでいい
Living Responsible Significant Role
責任ある重大な役割を生きる
think about how interesting it is
それがどれだけ面白いか考えてみる
Is this already mentioned?
これについてはすでに言及されていますか?
We talked about a lot of things in context
私たちは状況に応じて多くのことについて話しました
right
右
good
良い
So we started to focus on the research topic of educational diversion
そこで私たちは教育転用という研究テーマに焦点を当て始めました。
Let's say from the perspective of mental health trajectory
メンタルヘルスの軌跡の観点から言ってみましょう
We just have a set of topics
一連のトピックがあるだけです
we use it every time
私たちは毎回それを使用します
This group of questions is probably the only question
このグループの質問がおそらく唯一の質問です
guys i know some of you say
皆さん、私はあなた方の中にはこう言う人もいるのを知っています
when we visit
私たちが訪問するとき
Because he has answered it ten times
10回も答えてるから
so visit him
それで彼を訪ねてください
do you have this or something
これか何か持っていますか
none below none
なし以下なし
then turn the page
それからページをめくってください
Because he has answered more than ten times
10回以上答えてるから
He didn't even have that page
彼はそのページすら持っていなかった
just turn the page
ページをめくるだけ
don't suddenly grow old sometimes
時々突然老けないでね
still will be different
まだ違うだろう
still have to ask
まだ尋ねなければなりません
good
良い
Then our sample ranges from the first wave to the twenty-seventh year old
この場合、サンプルの範囲は第 1 波から 27 年目までになります。
I can show you
お見せできます
what about the other
もう一方はどうですか
Professor Fan Ganghua and I have worked together
范江華教授と私は一緒に研究してきました
We take high school or above
高校生以上を受験します
see how it's been for a while
しばらく様子を見てみましょう
Students who do not study because they graduated from junior high school
中学を卒業したからといって勉強しない生徒
Also the sample of departures is not that high
また、出発者のサンプルはそれほど高くありません
This is for everyone to see
これは誰でも見ることができます
This is the most typical
これが最も典型的なものです
In the growth process of Chinese and American teenagers
中国とアメリカの十代の若者の成長過程において
his melancholic state
彼の憂鬱かつ健康な状態
you can see
見ることができます
He started skyrocketing to 18 when he was 15
彼は15歳のときに18歳まで急上昇し始めました
very high
すごく高い
The red ones are women and the blue ones are men
赤いのが女性、青いのが男性です
black is average
黒は平均的
But from here, it began to slowly plateau
しかし、ここから徐々に停滞期が始まりました
This is what we call
これを私たちはそう呼んでいます
physiological maturation model
生理学的成熟モデル
this is a natural
これは自然なことです
Naturally it should look like this
当然、こうなるはずです
So what is Taiwan like?
では、台湾とはどんなところなのでしょうか？
is so
そうだね
Last time I told you a little bit about this
前回、これについて少しお話しましたが、
22 years old
22才
15 years old with the highest depression
最も深刻なうつ病を患う15歳
Why are you going to high school?
なぜ高校に行くのですか？
16 years old so happy
16歳、本当に幸せ
17 years old
17歳
At the age of 18, I started to be tall again, right?
18歳になってまた身長が伸び始めましたね。
going to university
大学に行く
we were weird
私たちは変だった
I don't know why 20 is so tall
なんで20歳であんなに背が高いのか分からない
Later we were thinking
後で私たちは考えていました
Some of the 20-year-olds have graduated from higher vocational schools
20代の中には高等専門学校を卒業した人もいます
Served in the military for two years
2年間兵役を務めた
he has his certain pressure
彼にはある種のプレッシャーがある
Back then we only saw here
あの頃はここしか見てなかった
then slowly descend
それからゆっくりと降りていきます
Is that so until 27
27までそうなんですか？
In fact, it should add 31
実際には 31 を追加する必要があります
Just need to continue to add 31
31 を追加し続ける必要があります
then you can watch girls
そうすれば女の子を観察できるよ
Girls are taller than boys all over the world
世界中で女の子の方が男の子より背が高い
But here there is a
しかし、ここには
When I graduated from university at the age of 22
22歳で大学を卒業したとき
is there a merge point
合流点はありますか
What about the boys?
男の子たちはどうですか？
Boys will be happier all the way
男の子はずっと幸せになるよ
But here he is taller
しかし、ここでは彼は背が高いです
22 years old when everyone graduated
みんなが卒業する頃には22歳
a little nervous scary
少し緊張して怖い
I went down again and felt good again
また下がってまた気持ち良くなった
Boys only feel good about themselves
男の子は自分だけが良いと感じる
I feel good about this quality
このクオリティは良い感じです
we will see later
後で見てみましょう
I will push and add a fun one for you to see
楽しいものをプッシュして追加しますので、ぜひご覧ください
remind me
思い出させて
Next, let's talk about the teacher
次に先生について話しましょう
that means let's go and see
それは、見に行きましょうという意味です
Educate your diversion about a person
人についての気晴らしを教育する
What is the effect
効果は何ですか
You see it's like a high school
まるで高校のようですね
15 18 22
１５ １８ ２２
This is a vocational college graduate
こちらは専門学校卒業生です
they are practicing
彼らは練習しています
This group has always had the highest
このグループは常に最高の成績を収めています
Has grown up
成長しました
Then this is high school
それからここは高校です
He only went to high school and didn't continue
彼は高校に行っただけで進学しなかった
You see he seems to be happy
あなたは彼をまるで幸せそうに見つめます
But at 22 he's a little nervous
でも22歳の彼は少し緊張している
Graduating from high school is somewhat different from graduating from higher vocational education in the job market
高校卒業と高等職業教育卒業は就職市場では多少異なります
Because your training human capital is not the same
トレーニングの人的資本が同じではないため
University of Science and Technology
科学技術大学
Technological universities are arguably doing well
工科大学は間違いなく好調だ
He's a little lower, a little lower all the way
彼は少し低い、ずっと少し低い
what about university
大学はどうですか
He's here, if you're a senior
あなたが先輩なら、彼はここにいます
He was tallest when he was 15
彼が一番背が高かったのは15歳の時だった
At the age of 18 is also the highest
身長も18で一番高い
At the age of 20, it is still quite tall, like high school
20歳でもまだ高校生くらいの身長ですね
But after you turned 24, did you notice him?
でも24歳になってから彼に気づきましたか？
rapid descent
急降下
Of course they have a commergence
もちろん彼らには商売があります
But at least he is the most descended
しかし、少なくとも彼は最も子孫です
Then let's say, let's see if there is any difference in the region
次に、地域に違いがあるかどうかを見てみましょう
Red is Taipei Line
赤は台北線
Is it a bit like a high school?
ちょっと高校っぽいかな？
that feeling
あの感じ
That Taipei City is this blue
台北の街がこんなに青いなんて
At first it seemed that Yilan was the happiest
最初は宜蘭が一番幸せそうに見えた
Just a little nervous at 20
20歳だとちょっと緊張する
to be honest
実を言うと
when i was getting ready i really felt
準備をしているときに本当に感じた
In 20 years, I really don't know more than I know
20年経っても本当に知らないことの方が多い
There are always questions coming out, I really don't know
いつも疑問が湧いてきますが、本当に分かりません
what's up with this 20 year old
この20歳はどうしたの？
i still don't know
まだ分​​かりません
so really sorry
本当にごめんなさい
I hope that someone will continue to study in the future
誰かが将来的に勉強し続けることを願っています
But you see that Yilan is really
でも宜蘭は本当にそうだね
quality of life will be better
生活の質が良くなる
So this thing makes us think
このことは私たちに考えさせます
Could it have something to do with the structure of his family?
それは彼の家族構成と関係があるのでしょうか？
family's structural capital
家族の構造資本
As far as we found out, this blue one is
私たちが調べた限りでは、この青いのは
Dad has a college degree or above
お父さんは大卒以上の学歴を持っている
Good shape
いい形
dad didn't
お父さんはしませんでした
You see, dad doesn't actually have
ほら、お父さんは実際には持っていない
always lower, right?
いつも低いですよね？
Especially in the 1920's it was obvious
特に1920年代にはそれが顕著だった
But at the age of 22
しかし22歳の時
The effect of the family's resources appears
家族の資源の効果が現れる
when you apply for a job
仕事に応募するとき
You will find that you have a father who is more educated
あなたにはもっと教育を受けた父親がいることがわかるでしょう
he can discuss with you
彼はあなたと話し合うことができます
I can tell you some things
いくつかのことをお伝えできます
It's different from nothing
何もないのとは違うよ
What about family relations?
家族関係はどうですか？
The blue one is a good family relationship
青いのは良好な家族関係
The red color means that the family relationship is relatively bad.
赤い色は家族関係が比較的悪いことを意味します。
As long as it is a bad relationship, it goes all the way and gets bigger and bigger.
悪い関係である限り、それはどこまでも広がり、どんどん大きくなっていきます。
It's because this study made me think of saying
この研究が私にこう言いたいと思わせたからです。
Although Yuyu's overall status and the two entrance exams correspond to each other
ゆゆの全体的なステータスと二つの入学試験は対応しているが
There is an obvious educational diversion effect
明らかな教育的転向効果がある
But the family vein has its double effect
しかし、家族の静脈には二重の効果があります
Appears in middle school and early adulthood
中学生から成人初期に現れる
and as it stands
そして現状では
like family relationship
家族関係のような
more pronounced than family structure
家族構成よりも顕著
We are here if you are interested in this
ご興味がございましたら、こちらまでお問い合わせください
welcome a lot of research
たくさんの研究を歓迎します
Because these materials have been released
これらの資料が公開されているので、
Anyone can go online to do academic research
誰でもオンラインにアクセスして学術研究を行うことができます
The growth trajectory of the school is obvious
学校の成長の軌跡が一目瞭然
has a long-term effect on
～に長期的な影響を与える
ok so here we go
さて、それでは行きましょう
I'll go on to say that sociologists care more about the underprivileged
続けて言いますが、社会学者は恵まれない人々のことをもっと気にかけています
among our vulnerable
私たちの脆弱な人々の間で
We have a set of questions that if you are interviewed here
ここで面接を受ける場合にいくつかの質問があります。
This is all about deviant behavior
これはすべて逸脱行為に関するものです
So I ask the current Taipei University
そこで現在の台北大学に聞いてみます。
Head of Department of Social Studies Chen Yifu
社会学部長 陳宜福
He was our first generation research assistant
彼は私たちの初代研究助手でした
So he went for three weeks
それで彼は3週間行きました
all week all weekend
今週ずっと週末ずっと
Just keep writing back and forth with me
私と往復書き続けてください
So this result is hot
したがって、この結果は熱いです
Everyone can take a look
誰でも見ることができます
we care about the disadvantaged
私たちは恵まれない人々を気にかけます
We also want to see from this
こちらからも見ていきたいと思います
What is the multi-development model?
マルチ開発モデルとは何ですか
Then if you say deviant behavior
じゃあ逸脱行為と言ったら
is a body indicator
ボディインジケーターです
so-called depressive symptoms
いわゆるうつ症状
It's a psychological indicator
心理的な指標です
Is there any correlation between these two indicators?
これら 2 つの指標の間に相関関係はありますか?
Here's what we all want to know
これは私たち一人ひとりが知りたいことです
right
右
someone nodded
誰かがうなずいた
Come on, let's take a look
さあ、見てみましょう
Indicators of our biased behavior
私たちの偏った行動の指標
Probably these ten
たぶんこの10人
result
結果
Melancholy, he used it from the age of 13 to the age of 18
メランコリー、彼は13歳から18歳まで使用していました
It was found that four groups can be distinguished
4つのグループに区別できることが分かりました
come everybody
みんな来てね
this
これ
This is called the highest
これを最高といいます
About 9.2% of him are tall all the way
彼の約9.2%はずっと背が高い
lowest here
ここで最低です
The lowest is of course the most
最低はもちろん最高です
he is always the lowest
彼はいつも最低だ
Turns out jumping a little bit at 15 when it was stressful
ストレスが溜まっていた15歳の時に少しジャンプしたことが判明
less obvious jump
あまり目立たないジャンプ
Another group of people in the literature
文学界の別のグループ
The literature will also tell you
文献も教えてくれます
He's going to have a flare-up in his mid-teens
10代半ばで再発するだろう
so parents don't be nervous
だから両親はゆっくりしてください
22% of this group of people
このグループの人々の 22%
In his 15-year-old burst he fell again
15歳の時の爆発で彼は再び転落した
So this group of people is normal
だからこの人たちのグループは普通なんだよ
Taiwan is different from Europe and the United States
台湾はヨーロッパやアメリカとは違う
That is to recall what I just said
それは私が今言ったことを思い出すことです
A whole bunch of us showing up another set
私たちの集団が別のセットを披露します
Blue will rise to the group at the age of 15 and 18
ブルーは15歳と18歳でグループに昇格する
I think this is really
これは本当にそうだと思います
Related to our educational diversion
教育転用に関連するもの
He is always there
彼はいつもそこにいる
under pressure
プレッシャーの下で
Some say he is 30 years old
30歳だという人もいる
I dreamed that he was taking an exam
彼が試験を受けている夢を見た
so many years
何年も
so you can see
それでわかります
This is with Mofit
これはモフィットと一緒です
His theory of deviant development is the same
彼の異常発達理論も同じです
It's just that we have one more in Taiwan
ただ、台湾にはもう一つあります
Deviation
偏差
so i want to say
だから私はただ言いたいのです
Then I see these four groups of people
すると、この 4 つの人々のグループが見えます
how about his depression
彼のうつ病はどうですか
Of course this thing is all the way up
もちろん、これはずっと上まで行きます
he is depressed
彼は落ち込んでいます
But in the end, there is not much difference
でも結局は大して変わらない
did you notice
気づきましたか
That group is what I'm talking about
私が話しているのはそのグループのことです
Nervous when the face is good
顔が良いと緊張する
This green is only once
この緑は一度だけ
This is relatively low
これは比較的低いです
no matter who you are at 15
15歳のあなたが誰であっても
all very nervous
みんなとても緊張しています
So the pressure of our high school entrance examination
高校受験のプレッシャー
We also talked about it last time
前回もお話しましたが
It is much more stressful than going to college
大学に行くよりずっとストレスがかかる
So this is his 19 to 30 years old
つまりこれは19歳から30歳です
You can see a little bump here
ここに小さな凹凸が見られます
But then converge again
しかし、その後また収束します
little difference
小さな違い
So overall
全体的に見て
You can see this line is very obvious
この線は非常に明白であることがわかります
We follow this wave all the way
私たちはこの波をずっと追いかけていきます
It's their link
それは彼らのリンクです
follow all the way
ずっと追いかけて
You can see this time low down
今度は下から見えます
go up again
もう一度上がってください
this time at the age of 20
今度は20歳の時に
This is the group I'm talking about
これが私が話しているグループです
Our special groups in Taiwan
台湾の特別グループ
He was very tall when he was 20 years old
彼は20歳の頃とても背が高かった
then to the back
それから後ろへ
Everyone is connected again
みんなまた繋がったね
so i'm interested
だから興味がある
I said okay don't let me take a look
わかった、見させないでと言いました
these four groups of people
この 4 つのグループの人々
After we control all the disguises
すべての変装を制御した後
Is this disguise still obvious?
この偽装はまだ明らかですか？
Then I present these salient
次に、これらの顕著な点を紹介します
show you please watch this
見せてください、これを見てください
It is the 9.2% just mentioned
今言った9.2％です。
The group with the highest deviant behavior all the way
逸脱行為が最も多いグループ
Indeed, there are many boys
確かに男の子が多いですね
He is likely to come from a single-parent family
彼は母子家庭の出身である可能性が高い
His highest education is lower than others, right?
彼の最高学歴は他の人より低いですよね？
Very high frequency of smoking
喫煙頻度が非常に高い
GPC we ask you how many packs you smoke a day, etc.
GPC では、1 日に何箱喫煙するかなどを尋ねます。
The question is very detailed, just to do some research
質問は非常に詳細なので、少し調べてください
And the frequency of drinking is also higher than others
そして飲酒頻度も他より高い
But is he the same as that
しかし、彼もそれと同じなのでしょうか？
his traditional gender role he is extra tall
彼の伝統的な性別役割 彼は非常に背が高い
It's more conservative. He will be more conservative.
もっと保守的だ、彼はもっと保守的になるだろう。
He is conservative in many views
彼は多くの観点から保守的だ
Although he has a high level of deviant behavior
彼は高度な逸脱行為を行っていますが、
In fact, his attitude is relatively conservative.
実際、彼の態度は比較的保守的です。
do you feel depressed
落ち込んでいますか
Actually not working class
実際には労働者階級ではない
Also more conservative than white-collar workers
ホワイトカラーよりも保守的でもある
This is certain at this time
これは現時点で確実です
All countries in the world are like this
世界中どこの国もこんな感じだよ
Okay, next family drama
さて、次はファミリードラマです
He was so low back then that's why he had all sorts of deviant behavior
当時の彼はとても落ち込んでいたので、あらゆる種類の逸脱した行動をとりました
Performance
パフォーマンス
Friends support, probably no one particularly likes this kind of person
友人のサポート、おそらくこの種の人を特に好む人はいないでしょう
So he is also very low
だから彼も非常に低いです
Married or not, of course not as good as this group
既婚であろうがなかろうが、もちろんこのグループほどではない
But I was very depressed and found that this is a very significant high
しかし、私は非常に落ち込んでおり、これが非常に大幅な高値であることがわかりました
He's most likely to start a business when he's 31
彼は31歳で起業する可能性が最も高い
And he earns more than all of them
そして彼は彼ら全員よりも多く稼いでいます
I'm relieved after we finally got this result the night before...
前夜にようやくこの結果が出て安心しました…。
Otherwise, I don't know how to tell you
そうでなければどうやって伝えればいいのか分かりません
So I'm going to tell you that after the high deviance group enters adulthood,
そこで私が言いたいのは、逸脱度の高いグループが成人期に入った後、
On the contrary, his entrepreneurship and his income are the highest
それどころか、彼の起業家精神と収入は最高です
So you need to know this
だからこれを知っておく必要があります
He's because of his high biased orientation
彼は非常に偏った方向性を持っているためです
So his explosive power will be different
だから爆発力が違うんだよ
So we are doing a very preliminary analysis of this thing now.
そこで私たちは現在、この件について非常に予備的な分析を行っています。
control a bunch of necessary disguises
必要な変装の束を制御する
It is also possible to obtain such remarkable results
このような素晴らしい成果も得られるのです
we have to prove it for him
私たちは彼のためにそれを証明したいと思っています
So next, some of our colleagues will do adult education and employment
次は、私たちの同僚の何人かが成人教育と雇用を担当する予定です
School to Work Transition
学校から職場への移行
This seems to be a very popular topic in the world
世間ではかなり話題になっているようです
Then our diversion is very similar to Germany
そうすると、私たちの転向はドイツと非常によく似ています
But it's not the same
しかし、それは同じではありません
When we were 15 years old, were we divided into high school and high school?
私たちが15歳のとき、高校生と高校生に分かれていましたか？
then divide later
後で分割する
that's for us
それは私たちのためです
We also have some special localization considerations
地域的に特別な考慮事項もいくつかあります
then we also want to know
それなら私たちも知りたいです
How is educational achievement related generationally
学歴と世代間の関係はどうなっているのか
School qualifications, occupations, etc.
学校の資格や職業など
so what
だから何
ok please take a look
わかりました、見てください
At the age of 31, our batch of samples
31歳のとき、私たちのサンプル群は
The actual degree is like this
実際の度数はこんな感じ
most are college graduates
ほとんどが大学卒業生です
Graduated from a junior college Graduated from a vocational school
短大卒業 専門学校卒業
Master's degree is very high
修士号は非常に高いです
Because now it's like a master's class
だって今は修士課程みたいなものだから
More open to young people to read
若者がよりオープンに読書できるようになる
we just say to us today
今日はただ私たちに言うだけです
take a look
見てください
when he was 15 or 18
彼が15歳か18歳のとき
we all asked a question
みんなで質問しました
How high of a degree do you hope you can study in the future?
将来どれくらいの学位を取得したいと思っていますか?
ok you can see
わかりました、わかります
When I graduated from junior high school at the age of 15
15歳で中学校を卒業したとき
Many people say that I will study until I graduate from a vocational school
専門学校を卒業するまで勉強するという人が多い
Do you have
ありますか
But when he was 18, he stopped talking like that.
しかし、18歳のとき、彼はそのように話すのをやめました。
But at the age of 31
しかし31歳の時に
The real degree is slightly higher
本当の度数はもう少し高い
Because maybe he missed
たぶん彼は見逃したから
master's degree
修士号
However, some subjective and objective conditions may not be able to match
ただし、主観的条件と客観的条件によっては一致しない場合があります。
so he moved up a little bit
それで彼は少し上に移動しました
so let's see
それでは見てみましょう
Therefore, the educator expects educational achievements similar to his own
したがって、教育者は自分と同様の教育成果を期待します。
We still have parents' educational expectations
私たちは依然として親の教育的期待を持っています
There are also teacher's educational expectations
教師の教育的期待もあります
Teachers and parents are quite converged
先生も保護者もしっかり集まっています
We also remember the children in Yilan
私たちは宜蘭の子供たちのことも覚えています
When I was in Guoyi, I was very happy that the volume chain was very high
Guoyiにいたとき、ボリュームチェーンが非常に高くてとてもうれしかったです
When he was in third grade, he would return to a comparison
３年生になったらまた比較に戻る
some practical expectations
いくつかの実際的な期待
so to speak
そう言える
good
良い
what's next
次は何ですか
Let's ask Professor Liu to take a look
劉教授に見てもらいましょう
What is the background profile of this sample?
このサンプルの背景プロファイルは何ですか?
About 38% are married
約38％が既婚者
23% have given birth
23％が出産済み
i am surprised
驚いています
32-year-olds think they are in normal health
32歳は自分たちは普通の健康状態だと思っている
I don't know why
どうしてか分かりません
i thought i should be happy
幸せになるべきだと思った
may be really ordinary
本当に普通かもしれない
That
それか
Then the father's family background
それから父親の家族背景
Father's college degree or above is 24
父親は24歳以上短大卒以上
Compared with the 70s we see now
今の70年代と比べると
It's a big difference
それは大きな違いです
so here
それでここで
This upward mobility in education is very evident
教育におけるこの上昇志向は非常に明白です
Then their income on average is like this
すると彼らの平均収入はこんな感じです
there are people in management
経営陣にも人がいる
probably the same
おそらく同じです
So
それで
The average number of years of schooling is 15.7
平均就学年数は15.7年
That
それか
come and see this
これを見に来てください
this is faster
これは速いです
About 70% of people are employed
約70％の人が就職している
But you need to know that the average company size is 3.5
ただし、平均的な企業規模は 3.5 人であることを知っておく必要があります。
so really small business
とても小さなビジネスです
Most of them are working in small companies.
彼らのほとんどは中小企業に勤めています。
Not the TSMC you think of
あなたが考えているTSMCではありません
absolutely not
絶対違う
probably so
おそらくそうだろう
good
良い
so what
だから何
By gender you can see
性別別に見てみると
If we divide it into four categories
4つに分類すると
This top national
この全国トップの
It is the classification of the ten schools listed by the Ministry of Education
文部省が列挙した10校の分類です。
Because I said that Taiwan is more interested in this
台湾の方がこれに興味があるって言ったから
Knowing that their final education is connected with his employment one by one
自分の最終学歴が就職に一つ一つつながっていることを知る
You see it is probably like this below the junior college level
短大レベル以下はおそらくこんな感じでしょうね
males are higher than females
男性は女性よりも高い
most at private colleges
私立大学ではほとんどが
This is no problem, probably everyone agrees
これは問題ありません、おそらく誰もが同意します
The average national university here is a little less than the top university
ここの平均的な国立大学はトップ大学よりも少し下です。
If the achievement of Fujing education
藤京教育の成果なら
The revival itself is below the specialist level
復活自体はスペシャリスト以下
This child is more likely to have only a junior college or below
この子は短大以下の大学しか卒業していない可能性が高い
or a private university
または私立大学
But if Fuxing has a college degree or above
ただし、復興が大学卒業以上の学位を持っている場合は、
he is in national university
彼は国立大学に通っています
You can see that compared to him, he will be obviously taller.
彼と比べると明らかに背が高いことがわかります。
So that's what we're talking about with shoulder flow
これがショルダーフローについて話していることです
This is the most basic one-by-one association
これは最も基本的な 1 対 1 の関連付けです
mother too
お母さんも
Then if you divide it again, you can see
もう一度分割してみるとわかります
Taipei is a national university and top universities
台北は国立大学でありトップクラスの大学です
It is higher than Taipei and Yilan
台北や宜蘭よりも高い
Taipei Line and Yilan can only be read in the language of colleges and universities
台北線と宜蘭は大学の言語でしか読めない
The proportion of those who did not study college is higher than that of Taipei City
大学に進学しなかった人の割合は台北市よりも高い
Regional differences exist
地域差が存在する
The distribution of educational resources is not the same
教育リソースの配分は一様ではない
So in the end we agreed
それで最終的には同意しました
Then let's see how your school and your labor market are doing.
次に、あなたの学校と労働市場がどのようになっているのか見てみましょう。
We take private universities
私立大学も受験します
More than half of the people are studying in private universities as a reference group
半数以上の人が私立大学を参考に学んでいる
Compared with him, those who did not go to university in college language
彼に比べて、大学に語学で行かなかった人は、
Compared with him, those who study in National University
彼に比べて、国立大学で勉強している人たちは
Those who go to top universities can compare with him
一流大学に通う人は彼と比較できる
Then empty out a lot of stuff
それから、たくさんのものを空にしてください
Discover Top National Universities for People
人々に人気の国立大学を発見する
It is more likely that the monthly salary is higher than that of private universities
私立大学よりも月給が高い可能性が高い
Gao Gao, this is the proof
ガオガオ、これが証拠だ
then this is about
それではこれについてです
National universities can have about 4% more
国立大学は約4％増額可能
And top universities can even reach
トップクラスの大学も到達できる
Twenty-two percent is 2 percent better than private universities
22% は私立大​​学より 2% 優れています
It's the same with the salary and the management class is interesting
給料もそうだし管理職も面白い
you'll find out you don't go to college
大学に行ってないことがわかるだろう
and only national university students
しかも国立大学生限定
with private university
私立大学と一緒
less likely to be a manager
マネージャーになる可能性は低い
Do you understand me?
あなたは私を理解していますか？
If you are studying at a private university
私立大学に在学中の場合
you don't go to college
あなたは大学に行っていません
And those who study in general state universities
そして一般の州立大学で学ぶ人たち
More opportunities to be a manager
マネージャーとして活躍できるチャンスが増える
But if the job is satisfactory
しかし、仕事が満足のいくものであれば、
Compared with private universities
私立大学と比べて
this person is satisfied
この人は満足しています
he didn't go to college
彼は大学に行っていませんでした
he's having fun too
彼も楽しんでいます
But with that national university
しかし、その国立大学では、
For top thousand universities
上位 1000 大学向け
Everyone is more satisfied than him
誰もが彼よりも満足している
What does this mean
これは何を意味するのでしょうか
family forced better
家族はより良いものを強制しました
Higher chances of entering national universities
国立大学に進学できる可能性が高くなる
this is what we've all been
これが私たち全員がそうだったことです
Repeated lectures on various educational research
各種教育研究についての繰り返し講義
And the salary after graduating from national university
そして国立大学卒業後の給料は
is relatively high
比較的高いです
Do you have
ありますか
This is not a problem
これは問題ではありません
so high tuition
とても高い授業料
this subsidy policy
この補助金政策は
Maybe it's really poor people who make up for it
おそらくそれを埋め合わせているのは本当に貧しい人々です
rich man
金持ち
This is indeed a concern
これは確かに懸念事項です
the other one
別のもの
This is a person from a private university
この人は私立大学の人です
percentage of his managerial positions
管理職に占める割合
is relatively high
比較的高いです
But he's not in a management position in a big company
でも彼は大企業の管理職ではない
So his salary is not high or low
だから彼の給料は高くも低くもない
and lower job satisfaction
そして仕事の満足度が低下する
so you know what I mean, right?
それで私が言いたいことはわかりますよね？
Then come and see
じゃあ見に来てね
His management experience will affect his future promotion
彼のマネジメント経験は彼の将来の昇進に影響を与えるだろう
Competing with his debts with others
他人と借金を競う
how will it develop
どのように発展するのでしょうか
I really want to see you again
本当にまた会いたいです
Only ten years later will we really know
本当にわかるのは10年後だけ
But that is to say, it can be seen that for us in Taiwan
しかし、つまり、台湾に住む私たちにとって、
When we divide it into private colleges most people practice
私立大学に分けるとほとんどの人が実践しています
General National Universities vs. Top Universities
一般国立大学 vs. トップ大学
You can see his way out is different
彼の出口が違うのがわかるだろう
So this article is mainly about this
ということで今回の記事は主にこれについてです
That's the last topic
それが最後の話題です
Marriage and childbirth of the younger generation
若い世代の結婚・出産
We have this issue of premarital sex and cohabitation
婚前交渉と同棲の問題があります
In fact, TYP may also be the first in Taiwan to do research
実際、TYP は台湾で初めて研究を行う可能性もあります。
Because these self-administered questionnaires
なぜなら、これらのアンケートは自己記入型だからです。
Ask some intimate questions about our sealed questionnaire
封印されたアンケートについていくつかの親密な質問をしてください
that's because of these
それはこれらのせいです
These samples have been with us for more than ten years
これらのサンプルは 10 年以上当社に保管されています
So he should have some trust in us
だから彼は私たちをある程度信頼しているはずだ
So they can fill out some smuggling questions themselves
彼らは密輸に関するいくつかの質問に自分たちで答えることができる
then we also want to know
それなら私たちも知りたいです
How does it affect the degree of marital satisfaction of married young couples
結婚した若いカップルの結婚生活の満足度にどのような影響があるか
Then let me show you the status of the marriage.
続いて結婚生活の様子をご紹介します。
about the information we collect
当社が収集する情報について
simply speaking
簡単に言えば
7% married by age 25
7%が25歳までに結婚
20% at age 28
28歳で20%
40% by 2017
2017 年までに 40%
I just said that it is consistent with the government's data
政府のデータと一致していると言いました
Let's count the number of people who got married
結婚した人の数を数えてみましょう
Probably using the government's ratio to calculate, there is only a difference of five or six.
おそらく政府の比率を使って計算すると、五、六の差しかない。
So there is 60%
つまり60％あります
Still unmarried at an average age of 31
平均年齢31歳で未だに未婚
So
それで
So the younger generation has premarital sex
だから若い世代は婚前交渉をする
let's just say when did you start
いつから始めたのか言ってみましょう
when was the first time
初めてはいつでしたか
let's ask this question first
まずこの質問をしてみましょう
Then want to know how your family and peers influence you
それから、家族や同僚があなたにどのような影響を与えているか知りたいです
that with or without premarital sex
婚前交渉の有無にかかわらず
What is its long-term effect
その長期的な影響は何ですか
We have a group of colleagues who are very concerned about this topic
私たちの同僚のグループはこの話題に非常に関心を持っています
Then the individual and various contextual factors
次に、個別およびさまざまな状況要因
It is also what we want to discuss, explain and clarify
それは私たちが議論し、説明し、明確にしたいことでもあります
Then this is a one-off survey.
それから、これは単発の調査です。
For example, our 2017
たとえば、2017 年の
Let's just say have you ever had premarital sex?
婚前交渉をしたことがありますか?
Then you will probably find that there are so many
そうすれば、たくさんあることがわかるでしょう
That is to say, you can see that the jump is very fast.
つまり、ジャンプが非常に速いことがわかります。
Then I will ask our assistant to do it this afternoon.
それから私たちのアシスタントに今日の午後にやってもらうことにします。
Because 60% of us are not married, right?
だって私たちの60％は結婚してないんですよね？
Among these unmarried samples
これらの未婚サンプルの中には
How did his sexual relationship, premarital intimacy develop?
彼の性的関係、結婚前の親密さはどのように発展したのでしょうか？
you can see it
見れば分かります
We had a group ask him how many of you have never had a boyfriend or girlfriend
私たちはグループに、彼氏や彼女がいない人が何人いるかを彼に尋ねました。
There are 302
302個あります
There are almost men and women here
ここにはほぼ男性と女性がいます
Have you never had sex before?
これまでセックスをしたことがないのですか？
girls taller
背の高い女の子
So is this group of nerds and nerds in our hearts?
では、このオタクとオタクのグループは私たちの心の中にあるのでしょうか？
31 years old never handed in never nothing
31歳は決して何も渡さなかった
sexual experience
性的経験
so we went to see him
それで私たちは彼に会いに行きました
The effect of the context and the effect of the peers are found
コンテキストの効果とピアの効果が分かる
If you are in school itself is a protection
学校にいる場合はそれ自体が保護になります
if you have community involvement you will lower your voice rate
コミュニティに参加している場合は、発言率を下げることになります
But if you're dating or have we asked you to mention
でも、あなたがデートしている場合、または私たちがあなたに言及するように頼んだ場合は、
Do you think your good friend has premarital sex? Some people talk about good friends without talking about themselves
あなたの親友は婚前交渉をしていると思いますか? 自分のことは話さずに親友のことを話す人がいます
Those who have good friends are more likely to happen.
仲の良い友達がいる人はそうなる可能性が高くなります。
So he thinks he is serious
だから彼は自分が真剣だと思っている
Then we can see
そうすればわかります
Therefore, the experience of premarital sex and cohabitation does increase premarital restoration and early marriage
したがって、婚前交渉と同棲の経験は、婚前修復と早期結婚を増加させます。
This is the research just done on behalf of Professor Tweety
これはトゥイーティー教授に代わって行われた研究です
Then I'll tell you something funny
じゃあ面白いこと言うよ
We have a very talented colleague who unfortunately left academia Mr. Li Ruizhong
私たちには、残念ながら学術界を去った非常に才能のある同僚、李瑞中氏がいます。
When he came to join our group, he said he was going to do a lab problem
彼が私たちのグループに参加しに来たとき、研究室の問題をやると言いました
In this experiment, one is five questions, and the other is one more question.
この実験では、1 つは 5 問、もう 1 つはさらに 1 問です。
It can be seen from that question
その質問からも分かる
did he have premarital sex
彼は婚前交渉をしましたか
As a result, I found that the experimental results of males are about 22 and 3
その結果、男性の実験結果は約22と3であることがわかりました。
female is 35
女性は35歳です
But when our research report asked him to self-report
しかし、私たちの調査報告書が彼に自己申告を求めたとき、
46 for men and 33 for women
男性46、女性33
Women's experiments are very similar to self-reports
女性の実験は自己報告に非常に似ている
Boys will touch, right?
男の子なら触りますよね？
Because he has some peer pressure, right?
彼には同調圧力があるからですよね？
i think this is so funny
これはとても面白いと思います
I didn't even think they should be 20 years old at that time
当時はまさか20歳になるとは思わなかった
is it 22
22ですか
i don't know i was at the time
私が当時いたかどうかはわかりません
I think this is so interesting
これはとても面白いと思います
It's a pity I didn't write it out
書かなかったのが残念です
I think this thing is still very interesting
これはまだ非常に興味深いと思います
Although men have about 2.1 times the
男性は約2.1倍ですが、
will explode his incidence rate
彼の発症率は爆発するだろう
But the female way of reporting is more reliable.
しかし、女性の報告方法の方がより信頼できます。
So you get what I mean
つまり、私の言いたいことはわかりますね
this is fun
これは楽しいです
Okay, I'm going to be Professor Yang Wenshan next.
さて、次はヤン・ウェンシャン教授になります。
Also our mortal colleagues
私たちの死すべき同僚たちも
cohabitation experience
同棲経験
His topic is very clear
他題目非常明確
What is the general rate of cohabitation?
一般的な同棲率はどれくらいですか？
What is his staged development?
彼の段階的な発達とは何ですか？
between gender and education
ジェンダーと教育の間
Does the difference matter
違いは重要ですか
Because we talked about premarital sex just now
さっき婚前交渉の話をしたから
you learn again
あなたはまた学びます
In fact, no longer learn to enter the social work
実際、ソーシャルワークに参加する方法を学ばなくなりました
Less likely to have premarital sex
婚前交渉をする可能性が低い
So school seems to be a protective factor
つまり、学校は保護要素のようです
what about cohabitation
同棲はどうですか
He tracked all the way from the age of 24 to 34
彼は24歳から34歳までずっと追跡しました
Cumulative distance of cohabitation
同棲の累計距離
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
at the age of 24
24歳のとき
About 6% for men
男性は6%くらい
7% for women
女性の場合は7%
slowly
ゆっくり
By the time of 27 28
27、28時までに
women are even slightly taller
女性の方が若干背が高いです
right
右
but in the end
しかし、最後には
Men will be higher than women
男性は女性よりも上位になります
This is traced all the way down
これはずっと下まで追跡されます
cumulative cohabitation rate
累計同棲率
If you use this to see
これを使って見ると
You can see about half of what didn't happen
起こっていないことの約半分がわかります
that this has happened
これが起こったことを
women than men
女性比男性
women are red
女性は赤い
slightly higher
やや高いです
but later on
しかし後で
until the age of 4
4歳まで
male taller
背の高い男性
Then look at his
それから彼のことを見てください
education level
教育程度
in the case of
の場合
below high school
高校以下
college and university
大学と大学
You will find that the less educated the more likely
教育が低いほどその可能性が高いことがわかります
There is a chance of this cohabitation
同棲の可能性もある
But after college
でも大学卒業後は
The difference between men and women is not that big
男女の差はそこまで大きくない
On the gender difference
性差について
There are gender differences between men and women beyond college
大学を超えても男女間には性差がある
not so big
それほど大きくない
So overall
全体的に見て
Our current young generation in Taiwan
台湾の今の若い世代
What is premarital intimacy really like?
結婚前の親密さは実際にはどのようなものですか？
I think premarital sex is fairly common
婚前交渉はかなり一般的だと思う
young adult
ヤングアダルト
About 80% said he had this experience
約80％がこの経験があると回答
while studying or not
勉強中でも、そうでなくても
There is also a significant influence of peers
仲間の影響も大きい
Second cohabitation is going up with age
2回目の同棲は年齢とともに上がる
About 50% said they had lived together
約50％が同棲経験があると回答
males outnumber females
男性の数が女性を上回ります
while the lower degree of university sex
一方、大学のセックスの程度は低い
People with a university degree will be lower
大卒の人はさらに低くなる
Then the sex difference will also decrease
そうすれば性差も縮まるだろう
So if this thing gives us an inspiration
このことが私たちにインスピレーションを与えるとしたら
As far as we're talking about marriage, it's obvious
結婚について話す限り、それは明らかです
Not for lack of intimacy
親密さの欠如ではない
but other economic
しかし他の経済的
social considerations
社会的配慮
So I'm going to tell you
だから私はあなたに言います
Some of the results we found with the directization study
直接調査で判明した結果の一部
but there is one
しかし、一つあります
One thing I find interesting is
私が興味深いと思うことの 1 つは、
60% of unmarried
60％が未婚
Nearly no intercourse Asexual relationship
性交渉がほぼない アセクシュアルな関係
This batch of slaughtering women is really worth noting
この一連の女性虐殺は本当に注目に値する
Because her number is not so small
彼女の数はそれほど少なくないので、
good
良い
Over the years we have
長年にわたり、私たちは
I've been doing sex interviews
セックスインタビューをしてきました
There are early marriages and ordinary marriages
早婚と普通結婚がある
unmarried
未婚
Let's talk about early marriage and low education
早婚と低学歴について話しましょう
and may have cohabitation experience
同棲経験もあるかもしれない
so straight interview
とてもストレートなインタビュー
We are in April this year
今年も4月に入りました
also reported last year
去年も報告されてた
What are the factors that affect early marriage
早婚に影響を与える要因は何ですか
can be roughly divided into three categories
大きく3つのカテゴリーに分けられます
Xiao Zhi I don't miss you see for yourself
Xiao Zhi、あなたが自分の目で確認できることを寂しくないです
Poor family relationship
家族関係が悪い
That means she doesn't have a good relationship with her previous generation of parents.
それは、彼女が前の世代の両親と良好な関係を持っていないことを意味します。
or the relationship between the parents
あるいは両親の関係
What we just said affects
私たちが今言ったことは影響を及ぼします
and native family
そして地元の家族
bad economic situation
悪い経済状況
so through marriage
だから結婚を通して
escape from family of origin
生まれ育った家族から逃げる
This is the first one I mentioned just now
これは今私が最初に言及したものです
avoid or need a
避けるか、必要とする
A relationship is put in it
関係性が込められている
The other is the influence of traditional cultural norms
もう1つは伝統的な文化規範の影響です。
especially married by decree
特に法令による結婚
Or want to have children before getting married
もしくは結婚前に子供が欲しい
or have lived together for a long time
あるいは長年一緒に住んでいる
Parents tell him to legalize
両親は彼に合法化するように言います
finally i saw one
ついに一つ見ました
I think it's normal
それが普通だと思います
impulse to love
愛する衝動
right
右
also have
也有
At that time, when I fell in love to a certain extent, I wanted to get married.
当時、私はある程度好きになり、結婚したいと思っていました。
You'd feel like seeing a marriage like this
こんな結婚生活を見たい気分になるだろう
just breathed a sigh of relief
ただ安堵のため息をついた
this is a comparison
これは比較です
Everyone will feel more
誰もがもっと感じるでしょう
result of relaxation
リラックスの結果
so unmarried
とても未婚です
we are now in
私たちは今います
reasons for engaging in unmarried
未婚でいることの理由
Probably can be divided into several
おそらくいくつかに分けられると思います
just now we said
今私たちは言いました
This is because traditional norms influence
これは伝統的な規範が影響を与えるためです
right
右
you were married by decree
あなたは法令により結婚しました
or how
あるいはどうやって
but in this place
でもこの場所では
It is also to challenge the traditional culture
伝統文化への挑戦でもある
i don't want to get married
結婚したくない
can also support yourself
自分自身をサポートすることもできる
I don't want to
したくない
offspring to marry
結婚する子孫
so he wants to be unmarried
だから彼は未婚になりたいのです
The second one has a poor relationship with the original family
二人目は元の家族との関係が悪い
Especially the relationship between parents
特に両親との関係
Ladies and gentlemen, this coincides with the love study I just talked about.
皆さん、これは先ほどお話しした恋愛の研究と重なります。
If there is conflict between parent and child
親と子の間に不和が生じた場合
Instead, he'll seek marriage and run away from the family.
代わりに、彼は結婚を求めて家族から逃げるでしょう。
When witnessing conflict between parents, especially as a teenager
特に十代の頃に両親間の対立を目撃したとき
often lowers him to get married
しばしば彼に結婚を勧める
Some thoughts on starting a family or having children
家族を始めることや子供を持つことについての考え
So our straightening and brightening here is completely consistent with the
したがって、ここでの矯正と明るくすることは、
There are several other reasons
他にもいくつか理由があります
Lack of incentives to enter married life
結婚生活を始める動機の欠如
I've been thinking about this for a long time, what should I do?
ずっと考えているのですが、どうしたらいいでしょうか？
and feelings that value stable relationships
安定した関係を大切にする気持ち
better than getting married
勝過結婚
Often he says he already has this partner
多くの場合、彼はすでにこのパートナーがいると言います
Seven years, eight years, nine years, ten years
7年、8年、9年、10年
just never thought of getting married
ただ結婚することは考えたこともなかった
This is quite common among young people in Taiwan
台湾の若者の間ではよくあることだ
Or married life is not free
あるいは結婚生活は自由ではない
The marriage process is fast and troublesome
結婚手続きは早くて面倒
we'll be fine
私たちは大丈夫です
How many people will there be
何人くらいいるんだろう
how much influence will he have
彼はどれだけの影響力を持つだろうか
Must wait until even we go to visit
私たちも訪問できるまで待たなければなりません
Several people said that they were supposed to be pregnant.
妊娠しているはずだったという人も何人かいた。
that must be married
それは結婚しているに違いない
Then you are not pregnant yet
じゃあまだ妊娠してないのね
So the wedding package still exists
ウェディングパッケージはまだ存在します
There are also people who are more obvious
もっとわかりやすい人もいるよ
Not many people are usually willing to say this
通常、これを積極的に言う人は多くありません
because we even in quantitative research
なぜなら、私たちは定量的研究でも
what do you think your ideal partner is
あなたの理想のパートナーは何だと思いますか
will check the economic clear
経済状況を確認します
Whatever condition is good is not the highest
どんなに状態が良くても最高ではない
We all get along and talk like this
みんなで仲良くこうやって話してます
I think it's not easy to talk all the time in marriage
結婚生活でずっと話し続けるのは簡単ではないと思う
Another one is
もう一つは、
He said that his love experience and dating partner are not suitable
恋愛経験も交際相手も合わないとのこと
or a bad love experience
または悪い恋愛経験
Or he thinks the partner is not suitable for marriage
あるいは相手が結婚にふさわしくないと考えている
only good for friends
友達だけに良い
But on the other hand we see
しかしその一方で、私たちは次のように考えています。
It was also stated in these interviews
こちらのインタビューでも語られていましたが、
i will get married in a year or two
私は1、2年以内に結婚するつもりです
ask him why
彼に理由を尋ねてください
He said it was because I was of marriageable age
彼は私が結婚適齢期だからだと言いました
So I think we actually have a chance
だから実際にチャンスはあると思う
to think young
若く考える
what is the marriageable age
結婚適齢期は何歳ですか
we asked some questions
私たちはいくつか質問しました
At what age do you think you should get married
何歳になったら結婚すべきだと思いますか
at what age should we start a family
何歳で家族を始めるべきか
When he found out that he was 25 years old, he said 28
彼は自分が25歳だと知ったとき、28歳だと言いました
When he was 28, he said 32
28歳の時は32歳って言ってた
just go all the way back
ただずっと戻ってください
This is also very honest
これもすごく正直なんです
Because it's over, what do you want?
もう終わったから何がしたいの？
so say
だから、言って
But the social norm of starting a family
しかし、家族を作るという社会規範
does still exist
確かにまだ存在します
So the last subtitle
それでは最後のサブ質問です
I told everyone
みんなに言いました
marital satisfaction for young couples
若いカップルの結婚生活の満足度
because we have now spoken
私たちは今話したので
40% of people are married
40％の人が結婚している
Among the 31-year-old married people
31歳既婚者の中で
Of course this includes his age of 25 and 28
もちろんこれには彼の25歳と28歳も含まれます
all married people
既婚者全員
their marriage is happy
彼らの結婚生活は幸せです
what kind of influence
どのような影響があるのか
Will it be the same as before
以前と同じになるでしょうか
you thought you said the same
あなたも同じことを言ったと思いましたか
You should be satisfied with Ike Arikawa
有川アイクなら満足できるはず
what do they think
彼らはどう思いますか
so what do i think about this thing
それで、私はこのことについてどう思いますか
We just want to see it from different sides
私たちはそれをさまざまな側面から見たいだけです
Then this article will also be published in October
それではこの記事も10月に掲載予定です
simply speaking
簡単に言えば
If you were to explain marital satisfaction
結婚生活の満足度を説明するとしたら
Like I said, there are too many times
言った通り、回数が多すぎる
It is really difficult to try my best to get rid of the pure scriptures
純粋な経典を取り除くために最善を尽くすのは本当に難しいです
Too many life stages are a thing
ライフステージが多すぎるのは問題だ
On the psychological level, your mother-in-law and daughter-in-law in childhood are all here
心理レベルでは、幼少期の義母と嫁がすべてここにいます
personal reason
一身上の都合
Family Economic Factors This is a set
家族の経済的要因 これはセットです
In addition, you can say that relational factors
さらに、関係要因とも言えます。
For example, if there is a lack of communication between newlyweds
例えば、新婚夫婦の間にコミュニケーション不足があった場合
Poor relationship between parent and adult child
親と成人した子供の間の関係が悪い
This will affect the marital satisfaction of young couples
これは若いカップルの結婚生活の満足度に影響を与える
In addition, many people in the West do gender role attitudes
さらに、西洋では多くの人が性別役割分担意識を持っています
think a person if gender role attitudes
性別役割に対する態度について考える
Believe that men and women should be more equal
男性と女性はもっと平等であるべきだと信じている
the better his marriage
彼の結婚生活がより良いものになればなるほど
But on the other hand, it is also found that husbands and wives compare
しかしその一方で、夫と妻が比較していることも分かりました。
If the wife has higher gender role attitudes than the husband
妻が夫よりも性役割に対する意識が高い場合
More equality is more detrimental to marriage satisfaction
平等が増すと結婚の満足度はさらに悪くなる
This goes back to the structural differences we talk about in sociology
これは、社会学で話されている構造的な違いに戻ります。
This is an attitude difference
これは態度の違いです
If there is too much difference between husband and wife
夫婦の差が大きすぎる場合
Usually he is not easy
通常他比較不容易
easy to produce good results
良い結果を生みやすい
What's the difference between east and west
東と西の違いは何ですか
The West will refer to research in recent years
欧米は近年の研究を参考にするだろう
will speak between spouses
夫婦間で話し合います
The importance of family factors
家族要素の重要性
think marital relationship
夫婦関係を考える
Husbands and wives feel differently
夫と妻では感じ方が違う
you can't just use one person
一人だけを使うことはできません
so we are lucky
だから私たちは幸運です
We ask the master sample again
マスターサンプルを再度お願いします
asked his spouse
彼の配偶者に尋ねた
on the same topic
同じ話題について
The two of them can have different answers
二人の答えは違うかもしれない
in addition
加えて
There are also differences in resources between husbands
夫婦間のリソースの差もある
There are also differences in the feeling of marriage relationship
夫婦関係に対する感覚の違いもある
it's all western research
それはすべて西洋の研究です
tell us what we should pay attention to
何に注意すべきかを教えてください
But in our Eastern social context
しかし、私たちの東洋の社会的文脈では
our patrilineal society
私たちの父系社会
Marriage was never a matter of two young people
結婚は決して二人の若者の問題ではなかった
it is a union of two families
それは二つの家族の結合です
So our previous
それで、私たちの以前の
not talking about marriage
結婚の話はしていない
It's about marrying a daughter-in-law
嫁との結婚についてです
marry a wife because
妻と結婚するので
Are you going to take a female
メスを連れていくのか
marry into this family
この家に結婚する
Then in this cultural context
そして、この文化的背景の中で
The relationship between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law is a good study
義母と嫁の関係は良い勉強になります
We are in this year's survey of seniors
私たちは今年のシニアアンケートに参加しています
We'll do some questions specifically on this
これについて具体的にいくつか質問します
Then exchange relatives with the three generations of the same family, etc.
それから三世代の同じ家族へ、親戚の交換など。
Simply put, our argument is
簡単に言えば、私たちの主張は次のとおりです
The current family system in Taiwan is a modified
現在の台湾の家族制度は改変されたものである
matriarchal family system
母系家族制度
In this system, cultural norms follow the genealogy of whether you are husband or wife
このシステムでは、文化的規範は夫か妻かという系図に従います。
is very important
はとても重要です
Therefore, the direct interaction must include structural relations and normative aspects.
したがって、直接的な相互作用には構造的関係と規範的側面が含まれなければなりません。
Study on the Core Keys of Marriage Satisfaction in Taiwan
台湾における結婚満足度の核心的鍵に関する研究
In fact, raising it a level or two is to ask this sentence
実際、レベルを 1 つまたは 2 つ上げるには、次の文を尋ねることになります。
Does Feminine Culture Persist? Or Has It Changed?
女性文化は存続しますか? それとも変化しましたか?
So if a marriage is not two parties but a union of two families
したがって、結婚が二者間の結合ではなく、二家族の結合であるならば、
Then marital satisfaction is not a feeling between two people
そうすると、結婚生活の満足感は二人の間で感じられるものではありません
It involves different inputs between the family level and the network of relatives and friends
それには、家族レベルと親戚や友人のネットワークの間でさまざまなインプットが含まれます。
OK, so we use
OK、それでは使用します
2014 and 2015 Spouse Survey
2014 年と 2015 年の配偶者調査
As a result, this thing may not be seen
その結果、このものが見られなくなる可能性があります
But basically a happy marriage
でも基本的には幸せな結婚生活
Everyone is satisfied
誰もが満足しています
So this means that you and
つまり、あなたと
Mother-in-law relationship or relationship with parents-in-law
義母との関係、または義父母との関係
You can see it roughly here
ここで大まかに見ることができます
Then we also constructed
それから私たちも構築しました
Did you live with your parents after you got married?
結婚後はご両親と同居されましたか？
with my husband a lot
夫と一緒にたくさん
Then the second is to live separately
2つ目は別居することです
The third is the right way
3番目が正しい方法です
Also this thing took some effort
これも少し手間がかかりました
we bring them to exchange
交換に持って行きます
In financial terms
金銭面で言うと
one is equal
一つは等しい
one is western
一つは西洋人です
one is partial husband
一人は片夫です
result
結果
We take the whole model
モデル全体を取り上げます
Divided into two categories of self-disguised phases
自己偽装フェーズの 2 つのカテゴリに分けられる
The first category is called resources
最初のカテゴリはリソースと呼ばれます
that includes these
これらを含む
family income etc.
世帯収入など
Wife is more educated
妻は高学歴です
Spouses are separated by resources
配偶者は資源によって隔てられている
The other category we call cultural norms
私たちが文化規範と呼ぶもう 1 つのカテゴリー
you can see it here
ここで見ることができます
Cultural norms have to live with
文化的規範は共存しなければなりません
There is a yin and qing relationship and a connection
陰と清の関係とつながりがあります
exchange etc.
交換等等
you can see the wife is affected
妻が影響を受けているのがわかります
very big
特別大
I list the notable ones
代表的なものを列挙します
not listed
記載されていない
It also affects the husband
夫にも影響が出る
For example, living with the husband
例えば、夫と同居する場合
Husbands who live apart are more satisfied
別居している夫の満足度が高い
but the interesting thing is
しかし興味深いのは
Compared with living with Husband Fang
ファン夫との暮らしと比べて
the few who live with their wives
妻と一緒に住んでいる少数の人たち
it's less
これは少ないです
The wife is dissatisfied
妻は不満を抱いている
so again
それでまた
I found that at different stages
さまざまな段階でそれを発見しました
unconventional atypical arrangement
型破りな変則的な配置
often lead to negative effects
悪影響をもたらすことが多い
This quantitative research can be said here
この定量的調査はここで言えます
Why
なぜ
May need some straightforward additions
いくつかの簡単な追加が必要な場合があります
on the other hand
一方で
we found westward
西の方角で見つけた
yes can bring some benefits
はい、いくつかの利点をもたらすことができます
but negative relationship
でもネガティブな関係
very important
とても重要な
Husband thinks he is with
夫は一緒にいると思っている
The more women get along with the mother
母親と仲良くなる女性が増えるほど
have some pressure
ある程度のプレッシャーがある
or when he feels less than ideal
または彼が理想より劣っていると感じたとき
he is
彼は
no matter husband or wife
夫でも妻でも関係なく
are equally affected
等しく影響を受ける
But for the wife
でも妻にとっては
When he has problems with his in-laws
義理の両親と問題を抱えているとき
he will be affected
彼は影響を受けるだろう
So the conclusion of this study
したがって、この研究の結論は
just tell us
教えてください
Let's look at it theoretically
理論的に見てみましょう
Actually resources and cultural norms
実際には資源と文化規範
will have an important impact
重要な影響を与えるだろう
And we are doing some further analysis
そして私たちはさらなる分析を行っています
I didn't release it here
ここでは公開しませんでした
That is, the cultural norm is that wives are happy in marriage.
つまり、妻は結婚生活で幸せであるというのが文化的規範です。
I just said
私はちょうど言いました
it makes a big impact
それは大きな影響を与えます
However, if we further de-interact
ただし、さらに対話を解除すると、
It was discovered that she was living with her husband's parents
夫の両親と同居していることが判明
And she's a full-time working wife
そして彼女はフルタイムで働く妻です
The most obvious impact
最も明らかな影響
It is most likely to have negative effects
悪影響を与える可能性が最も高い
That's it
それでおしまい
So if the wife here is working full time
ここの妻がフルタイムで働いている場合
Because I live with my husband's parents
夫の両親と同居しているので
Pay more attention to give more support
より多くのサポートを提供するために、より注意を払う
Then if the husband feels negative
それで夫がネガティブな気持ちになったら
Negative relationship will lead to both husband and wife
否定的な関係は夫と妻の両方につながります
Negative Effects of Marital Satisfaction
夫婦の満足度の悪影響
So what is the reflection of this thing for me?
それで、このことは私にとって何を反映しているのでしょうか？
Taiwanese family
台湾人の家族
In fact, many places are still traditional
実際、多くの場所には伝統が残っています
The impact with the modern
現代への影響
pick there
そこで選んでください
and compromise and make some responses
そして妥協して何らかの対応をする
because of our values
私たちの価値観のせいで
some of our actions are continuous
私たちの行動の中には継続的なものもあります
some are constant
一部は一定です
So if Taiwan still has an East Asian society
もし台湾にまだ東アジア社会があるとしたら
We are different from Europe and the United States
私たちはヨーロッパやアメリカとは違います
because you study a family in transition
移行期の家族を研究しているからです
Needs to go beyond your interpretation of personal resources
個人リソースの解釈を超える必要がある
The interaction of cultural norms should also be considered
文化的規範の相互作用も考慮する必要がある
I also believe that this is our social science community in Taiwan.
私はまた、これが台湾の社会科学コミュニティであると信じています。
Family studies can be done internationally in academia
家族研究は学術界で国際的に実施可能
where you can make a little contribution
少しでも貢献できる場所
Because instead of just applying some western theories
なぜなら、西洋の理論をただ適用するのではなく、
resource theory
資源理論
what kind of resources
どのようなリソースですか
When we add the importance of cultural norms
文化的規範の重要性を加えると
they will find
彼らは見つけます
At least in this large area with a large population
少なくともこの広い人口の多い地域では
it's very important
それは非常に重要です
There are already so many slopes in our current data release
現在のデータリリースにはすでに非常に多くの勾配があります
Welcome everyone to apply with the research office to use
皆さんもぜひ研究室に申請して利用してください
20 years
20年
Then we also published two books in English
その後、英語で本を2冊出版しました
Now our second English book
さて、2冊目の英語の本です
in preparation probably there will be
準備中、おそらくあるでしょう
16 to 18 papers for Phase 2 results
フェーズ 2 の結果については 16 ～ 18 件の論文
then in the end i was
そしてついに私は
thank you very much
どうもありがとうございます
most grateful
最感謝的
They are all samples of our young people
彼らは皆、私たちの若者のサンプルです
They are willing to continue to be us
彼らは私たちであり続けることに意欲的です
visit for more than an hour every time
毎回1時間以上訪問する
200 yuan
200元
Very sorry
本当にごめんなさい
Then
それから
and our parents
そして私たちの両親
Especially this year we are going to
特に今年は、
Sixth Wave 62-Year-Old Parents Study
第 6 ウェーブの 62 歳の両親の調査
I don't know how many parents
他に何人の親がいるか分からない
willing to answer
喜んで答える
But at least in the first five waves
しかし少なくとも最初の5波では
we are very grateful to them
私たちは彼らにとても感謝しています
then this year we will try
それなら今年はやってみます
That is, outside of one of the parents
つまり、両親のどちらか以外では、
another one
もう一つ
We also do a short roll of visits
短期訪問も行っております
hope that the relationship between parents
両親の関係がうまくいくことを願っています
problems condensed together
問題が凝縮されている
The teacher and principal of the junior high school
中学校の先生と校長
Especially middle school teachers
特に中学校の先生は
can you imagine
想像できますか
I took the entrance exam in July and June
7月と6月に入学試験を受けました
September asked him what his test score was
セプテンバーは彼にテストの点数を尋ねた
He told you to forget
彼はあなたに忘れるように言った
Fortunately, we asked the teacher
幸いなことに、私たちは先生に尋ねました
teachers have records
教師は記録を持っています
So we use the teacher
そこで先生を使います
So these kids are very prosperous
ですから、この子供たちはとても裕福です
Then, I really want to thank these principals
それでは、校長先生たちに本当に感謝したいと思います
Except for one, he said he had a heart for the job, and he didn't answer.
1人を除いて、彼はこの仕事に熱意を持っていると言いましたが、答えませんでした。
In fact, each of his principals is interested in community resources.
実際、校長たちはそれぞれ地域のリソースに関心を持っています。
How does the school respond to these needs?
学校はこうしたニーズにどのように対応しているのでしょうか？
Give us some good information
良い情報を教えてください
We are also very grateful to all the guides and interviewers
ガイドやインタビュアーの皆様にも大変感謝しております
I think there is something in it today
今日は何かあると思う
This is a special thank you to everyone
これは皆さんへの特別な感謝です
If it weren't for you to go this way one by one
あなたがいなかったら、一つ一つこの道を進んで行ったのなら
If you look at it, we have too many messages and can’t do it
見てみるとメッセージが多すぎて無理です
it's really not easy
それは本当に簡単ではありません
Moreover, our guides and interviewers are carefully selected.
また、ガイドや面接官も厳選しております。
special thanks
特別な感謝
We also thank all participating research colleagues
参加した研究同僚の皆様にも感謝いたします
There are quite a few of them today
今日はかなりの数があります
There are people before and after us
私たちの前にも後ろにも人がいます
Especially our former and former research assistants
特に元および元研究助手
with all our postdocs
私たちのポスドク全員と
We originally said that from the first generation
もともと初代からそう言ってた
How many generations of research assistants have there been
研究助手は何世代いますか
We're all going from middle age to old age too.
私たちも中年から老年へと移ります。
We would like to thank the Chinese
私たちは中国人に感謝したいと思います
Deputy Director Nakazonozono
中園園院方副院長
There are also social institutes
社会機関もあります
Especially the administrative colleagues are too busy to help
特に管理部門の同僚は忙しすぎて手伝うことができません
such a big study
こんなに大きな研究
You can imagine how complicated he is
彼がどれほど複雑であるか想像できるでしょう
The Ministry of Science and Technology of the National Science Council has also supported it all the way to this day
国家科学会議の科学技術省も今日に至るまでこれを支援している。
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thank you very much Professor Ying
英教授、本当にありがとうございました
very brilliant and interesting research
非常に素晴らしく興味深い研究
Absolutely worthy of our hospital's strong support
当院の強力なサポートが絶対に必要です
what about now
今はどう
We will open this time to all listeners
今回はリスナーの皆様に公開いたします
Let's see if you have any questions
何か質問があれば聞いてみましょう
We are now open to everyone
今では誰でもご利用いただけます
ok sir
わかりました、先生
Come on
来て
ask the professor
教授に聞く
The new syllabus we are now implementing
現在導入している新しいシラバス
Right, starting this year
そうそう、今年から
a child of christ
キリストの子
and adult
そして大人の
parents
両親
do grandparents
祖父母がやる
How to express the country's new curriculum
国の新しいカリキュラムをどう表現するか
Empower children to compete in entering
子どもたちに競争力を与えて入学できるようにする
Won't
しません
Lack
足らない
Thanks
ありがとう
You're younger and I can't get mad
あなたは年下だから怒ることはできない
besides
そのほか
Collect some topics together
いくつかのトピックをまとめてみる
Let Professor Ying answer him together
イン教授に一緒に答えてもらいましょう
Are there any other questions?
他にご質問はありますか?
Will it make a difference for me to say that?
私がそれを言うことで何かが変わるでしょうか？
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
This question about the new syllabus
新しいシラバスに関するこの質問
because it happened in recent years
それは近年起こったことだから
We did it in 2000
2000年にやりました
So at that time for us it was
つまり、当時の私たちにとってそれは
From joint examination system to
共同審査制度から
partial application
部分適用
So education reform attendance is in that place
教育改革の出席はそこにあるのですね
so we didn't touch the new syllabus
だから私たちは新しいシラバスには触れませんでした
should say like this
このように言うべきです
It should be said that the advantages of TYP are
TYP の利点は次のとおりであると言えます。
At that time, it can still be approved by the principal
その際、ご本人の同意を得た上で
Education Bureau agrees
教育局同意
we can do a whole class survey
クラス全体のアンケートを行うことができます
now includes DH several years ago
数年前からDHも含まれるようになりました
Did you hear they're going to do a class survey?
授業アンケートをするって聞いた？
subject to parental consent
保護者の同意が必要です
The sample of that thing is not right anytime soon
あれのサンプルはすぐに正しくなくなります
Then it becomes what we call deviation
そうなると、いわゆる偏差値になります
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
Is BioS biased?
BioSは逸脱しますか？
not a biased sample
偏ったサンプルではない
biased sample words
偏ったサンプル単語
It is not suitable for us to do these studies
私たちがこれらの研究を行うのはふさわしくない
so we are lucky
だから私たちは幸運です
Then about education reform
次に、教育改革についてです。
Between the new system and the inauguration
新体制から発足までの間
The information we can provide is
私たちが提供できる情報は、
what we just said
私たちが今言ったこと
The new system brings more obvious
新しいシステムにより、より明確な結果が得られます
social class inequality
社会階級の不平等
That is, I just had
つまり、ちょうど持っていた
sorry i just repeat
ごめんなさい、繰り返します
that is
あれは
twenty five percent
二五パーセント
Households in the top 25 percent of income
収入上位 25% の世帯
Chances for his children to attend star high schools
彼の子供たちがスター高校に通うチャンス
very significantly high
非常に大幅に高い
So this is probably what we can think of here
ここで考えられるのはおそらくこれです
Then admit the sample before merging
その後、合流する前にサンプルを受け入れます
We have found that the combination of these two groups of samples probably has no major problems in other aspects
これら 2 つのサンプル グループの組み合わせには、他の側面ではおそらく大きな問題がないことがわかりました。
so we just merge it
だからそれをマージするだけです
The new curriculum must follow
新しいカリキュラムは従わなければなりません
Only recently started to matter
最近になって問題になり始めた
just we
私たちだけ
These samples are all too old to be 31 years old
これらのサンプルは 31 歳とは思えないほど古すぎます。
Hehehe
ふふふ
but thank you for asking
でも質問してくれてありがとう
Hello Professor
こんにちは教授
Thank you very much for your efforts
ご尽力いただき誠にありがとうございました
i want to ask a question
私は質問をしたいです
Because I think you are very concerned about this so-called vulnerable group
というのは、あなたはこのいわゆる社会的弱者のことを非常に懸念していると思うからです。
I think we have what's called affectionate disorder
私たちはいわゆる愛情障害だと思います
such a person
そんな人
During the whole development process, he didn't know if there was any in you
開発プロセス全体を通じて、彼はあなたの中に何かがあるかどうか知りませんでした
especially to track or say
特に追跡したり言うこと
you on this
あなたはこれについて
you
あなた
do you have any such a plan
そのような計画はありますか
Some simple assessments can be made on this scene in Taiwan
台湾のこの光景について、いくつかの簡単な評価ができる
or
また
right
右
Thank you for your question
ご質問ありがとうございます
us
私たち
Generally speaking, we take the hospital of traditional Chinese medicine to be responsible for promoting another big investigation
一般的に言えば、私たちは中医病院が新たな大規模な調査を推進する責任があると考えています。
From the survey of social change in Taiwan
台湾の社会変動調査より
Before I borrowed time, we all had special inquiries about the need for some disabled people in the family.
私が時間を借りる前に、家族の中に障害のある人が必要であることについて、私たち全員が特別な問い合わせをしていました。
That number is usually too small in the overall survey
この数字は通常、調査全体からすると小さすぎます
Based on our own survey
当社独自の調査に基づく
Why did I specifically mention deviant behavior
なぜ逸脱行為について特に言及したのか
because that's what we can gather
それが私たちが集められるものだから
we have noticed
私たちは気づきました
I don't know if you guys really remember
そのとき、皆さんが本当に覚えているかどうかはわかりませんが、
At that time, I will say that our English is called
そのとき、私たちの英語はこう呼ばれると言うでしょう
Taiwan Youth Survey
台湾青少年調査
Don't talk about Taiwan Youth Project
台湾青少年プロジェクトについて話さないでください
I said I don't want because we have no strength
力がないからいらないって言った
we don't have social workers
うちにはソーシャルワーカーがいない
And we don't have a counselor
そしてうちにはカウンセラーがいない
If you need psychological counseling
心理カウンセリングが必要な場合
what do we do when the parents call
親から電話が来たらどうするか
But everyone was young back then
でもあの頃はみんな若かった
Everyone says they want to
誰もがしたいと言う
so i remember i was serious so
だから私は真剣だったことを覚えています
Get to know some psychology of Yilan County
宜蘭県の心理を知ろう
sorry psychiatrist
ごめんなさい精神科医
I'll just say we know he has this problem
彼がこの問題を抱えていることはわかっているとだけ言っておきます
the teacher reacted
先生は反応した
I asked the doctor to say
私は医者にこう言いました
You can go to this school to help
この学校に行って助けてもらえますか
Then I found out that their school is high school
その後、彼らの学校は高校であることがわかりました
their referral
彼らの紹介
The referral referral system is not like this
紹介紹介制度はこんなものではありません
Be sure to contact your tutor with them
必ず講師に連絡してください
The hospital can't go there to take the baby away
病院は赤ちゃんを引き取りに行くことはできません
I also remember
私も覚えています
A father specifically called to say
父親がわざわざ電話してこう言いました
why don't you guys visit me this year
今年は私のところに来ませんか？
how can i tell him
どうやって彼に言えばいいですか
Because his son is gone
息子がいなくなってしまったので
his son left
彼の息子は去った
if his son leaves i want him
彼の息子が去ったら私は彼が欲しい
I can't help it
仕方ないよ
I can't get in touch with his son
息子と連絡が取れない
At that time I felt really sad
その時は本当に悲しい気持ちになりました
then we have some mothers
それから私たちには母親が何人かいます
also called
とも呼ばれている
Let's just say that the son is the otaku we just talked about
息子が先ほど話したオタクだとしましょう。
college graduates do nothing
大卒は何もしない
He said nobody cares
彼は誰も気にしないと言った
but the strange thing is
しかし奇妙なのは
tip interviewer calls
tip訪員打電話
make an appointment with him
彼と約束をする
he said yes
彼はそうだと言った
wow this mama washes out
うわー、このママは洗い流します
called several times and said
何度か電話してこう言いました
can you please
お願いできますか
just please let him come to your place
ただ彼をあなたの家に来させてください
for free
無料で
Just when your princess was born
ちょうどあなたのお姫様が生まれたとき
just let him go
ただ彼を行かせてください
Just go out and help
ただ外に出て手伝うだけ
you can see this happening
これが起こっているのがわかります
few others
他に数人
we have no way
私たちには方法がありません
as an adult
大人として
there is no way to track like this
このように追跡する方法はありません
So I always feel very owed
だから私はいつもとても負い目を感じています
Not only research does not know more than the system
研究はシステム以上のことを知らないだけではありません
in difficult situations
困難な状況で
We can't help enough
私たちは十分に助けることができません
Really are
本当にそうです
So we just hope that at least
したがって、少なくとも次のことを願っています。
let us know
我々に教えてください
in deviant behavior
逸脱した行動で
They were looked down upon from childhood
彼らは子供の頃から見下されていた
there is a problem
問題があります
In fact, he is likely to start a business in the future.
実は彼は将来起業する可能性があるそうです。
So give humanity a little hope
だから人類に少しの希望を与えてください
you don't know
あなたは知りません
Are there any other questions?
他にご質問はありますか?
good
良い
there are several questions here
ここにいくつか質問があります
one two three
一 二 三
from this young man
この青年から
hello professor
こんにちは教授
I just want to ask
ただ聞きたいのですが
about teens in
の十代の若者たちについて
The part of bullying between the possible fellow
可能性のある仲間同士のいじめの部分
for their growth
彼らの成長のために
Except we usually
普段の私たちを除いて
Regret that linear thinking may produce
直線的な思考が生むかもしれない後悔
Is there anything else that was accidentally discovered in the research?
研究中に偶然発見されたものは他にありますか?
As for my reporter's answer
記者の答えとしては
If I forget, trouble the two teachers to add
忘れたら二人の先生に追加してもらってください
I reporter we have had to ask
記者は尋ねなければならなかった
a problem called school bullying
学校のいじめという問題
we even then
私たちはそれでも
I still remember if Teacher Yawenshan said
ヤウェンシャン先生がこう言ったかどうかを今でも覚えています。
Many junior high school students join gangs
暴力団に加入する中学生も多い
Do you have
ありますか
At that time, we also followed the newspapers
当時、私たちも新聞を追っていました
we also asked
私たちも尋ねました
But too few people come out
でも出てくる人が少なすぎる
because you need to know
あなたは知る必要があるから
That's not to say too little doesn't matter
少なすぎても問題ないというわけではありません
It's that we have no way to process this data
このデータを処理する方法がないということです
Among your five thousand people
あなたの5000人の中に
For example we even ask
たとえば、私たちは次のように尋ねます。
Your first sex was forced
あなたの最初のセックスは強制的でした
We also asked this question
こんな質問もさせていただきました
All four thousand people came down
四千人全員が降り立った
forty eight
四十八個
What about forty-eight if
48 ならどうでしょうか
You're going to do something special that's hard to do
あなたは何か特別なことをするのですが、それは難しいことです
there is no way
道はない
48 more than no
48 ないより多い
or 48 than yes no
または 48 よりも はい いいえ
This 48 is too small, everything is too small
この48は小さすぎる、すべてが小さすぎる
So I remember we had this problem
それで、この問題があったことを覚えています
Just asking if you ever joined a gang
ギャングに入ったことがあるかどうかを尋ねるだけです
Actually this is
実はこれは
Sociology is different from journalism
社会学はジャーナリズムとは異なります
journalism for this particular
この特定のジャーナリズム
it can write a long article
長い記事を書くことができる
Makes you feel like everything is in danger, doesn't it?
すべてが危険にさらされているように感じますよね？
Then we also hope to be able to fight against grass and trees
そうすれば草や木とも戦えるようになりたいと思っています
do a little proof but
少し証明してみますが、
Too little data age
データの経過時間が少なすぎる
So that school bully you want special sampling
学校のいじめっ子が特別なサンプリングを望んでいるように
maybe more likely
おそらくもっと可能性が高い
Because we used to have a part-time assistant
パートのアシスタントがいましたので
Later, at the Chinese University of Hong Kong, those social work doctors
その後、香港中文大学でソーシャルワークの医師たちが
He can't use TYP
彼はTYPを使えない
to do school bullying
学校でいじめをする
Instead, special sampling is required
代わりに、特別なサンプリングが必要です
Probably so, right?
おそらくそうですよね？
Hello Professor, my problem is more troublesome
こんにちは、教授、私の問題はもっと厄介です
older is
年上です
Our teenagers in Taiwan now
現在台​​湾にいる私たちの十代の若者たち
His ingredients may not only be
彼の成分は単に
native of taiwan
台湾出身
He may also include family members like outsiders
部外者のような家族も含まれる場合がある
or planning a family
または家族の計画を立てている
I don't know about you in that regard
その点ではあなたのことは知りません
Did you discover something during your process?
その過程で何か発見はありましたか？
The second is about education
二つ目は教育についてです
That's what we did when you started in 2000
あなたが 2000 年に始めたときに私たちがやったことはそれです
That was between 2000 and 204 to 2008
それは 2000 年から 204 年から 2008 年までの間でした
Taiwan has already begun to have so-called home education
台湾ではすでにいわゆる家庭教育が始まっている
or non-school style education of these families
またはこれらの家庭の非学校教育
I don't know you guys are in the process of adjusting
皆さんが調整中なのか知りません
Has there been such a case?
そのようなケースはありましたか？
how do you deal with it
どのように対処しますか
thanks for asking the first question
最初の質問をしてくれてありがとう
i wish someone would ask
誰かが聞いてくれたらいいのに
because we had
私たちが持っていたから
we spent a month or two
私たちは1ヶ月か2ヶ月を過ごしました
Sort out mother or father
母親か父親を整理する
Children whose place of birth is not in Taiwan
出生地が台湾以外の児童
The result is probably out
結果は出てるかも
If I remember correctly it is more than 100
記憶が正しければ100以上です
Then he is almost 60% in the mainland station
それから彼は本土ステーションにほぼ60％います
I thought it was great
すごいと思いました
We this is the characteristic of our Zhihua sample
これが当社のZhihuaサンプルの特徴です
so i remember we were
だから私たちはそうだったのを覚えています
A certain area in Donglu, Nanjing
南京市東廬のとあるエリア
ask him to discuss
彼に話し合うよう頼む
Just interview him and an assistant
彼とアシスタントにインタビューしてください
It's not easy to get a date and I'm happy
デートするのは簡単じゃないけど嬉しい
As a result, there is no way to do it
結果的にはどうすることもできない
because we are too early
私たちは早すぎるから
his mother is indonesian
彼の母親はインドネシア人です
He told me that I was born a few years earlier
数年早く生まれてよかったって彼は言ってくれた
At that time my classmates said
その時クラスメイトが言いました
your mother is a foreigner
あなたのお母さんは外国人です
He said if I was born late
もし私が遅く生まれたら彼は言った
five years ten years bad
5年10年悪い
I became a child of a foreign spouse family
外国人配偶者家庭の子となりました
my puppet
私の人形
that way
そうやって
Indeed I did not consider the location
確かに場所は考えていませんでした
That is to say, our entry point is the year 2000
つまり、入り口は 2000 年です。
even said
さえ言った
He was Guoyi at that time
当時彼はGuoyiでした
He didn't feel discriminated against
彼は差別されているとは感じなかった
On the contrary, he is very proud in class
それどころか、彼はクラスではとても誇りに思っています
because mom is a foreigner
お母さんが外国人だから
you understand me so well
あなたは私のことをとてもよく理解しています
So this discriminatory nature of foreign assignments
外国赴任のこの差別的な性質は
Although the number of people who followed him
彼をフォローした人の数は
and quality
そして品質
But it is more of a social ethos
しかし、それはむしろ社会的倫理です
I always tell you a fact
私はいつもあなたに事実を言います
if we say
私たちが言うなら
Less educated outsiders
教育水準の低い部外者
The education level of the person who begs you to marry him
結婚してほしいと懇願する人の学歴
Is it higher?
もっと高いですか？
It is who in our Taiwanese society marries whom
私たちの台湾社会では、誰が誰と結婚するかが重要です
so i keep saying
だから私は言い続けます
If the expatriate family comes to Taiwan
駐在員家族が台湾に来る場合
them
彼ら
Didn't come to change our family system
私たちの家族制度を変えるために来たわけではない
They bring in some new cultural elements
彼らはいくつかの新しい文化的要素を持ち込んでいます
it is possible they are
彼らはそうである可能性があります
Cooking is different
料理も違うし
All aspects of diet
食事のあらゆる側面
However, the entire family accommodation still maintains considerable integrity.
しかし、家族向け宿泊施設全体は依然としてかなりの完全性を維持しています。
As for the changes you said after 2008
2008年以降の変化については
Because we've moved beyond that time
僕らはあの時を超えてしまったから
That is to say, this group of people are all national first or third nationals in 2000.
つまり、このグループの人々は全員、2000 年時点で第一国籍か第三国籍を取得した人たちです。
Every time we recruit our assistants, we must have such a person
アシスタントを募集するときは必ずそのような人が必要です
we just looked at him thinking we were visiting him
私たちは彼を訪ねているのだと思って彼を眺めただけでした
So Xuanyuan told me that he is the last Guoyi sample
それでXuanyuanは私に、彼が最後のGuoyiサンプルであると言いました
The next assistants are all smaller than this
次のアシスタントはすべてこれより小さいです
you can say it like this
このように言えます
So we say there's something wrong with them watching him
だから私たちは、彼らが彼を見ているのは何か問題があると言っています
sometimes ask their opinion how they feel
時々彼らがどう感じているか意見を尋ねます
The teacher is very interesting
先生はとても面白いです
Then we're the last one or two
それでは私たちが最後の 1 人か 2 人です
good
良い
so
それで
hello i want to ask
こんにちは、聞きたいです
That's the one you mentioned about flagging
それはあなたがフラグについて言及したものです
For his subsequent entrepreneurship, he still has a higher income
その後の起業で、彼は今でもより高い収入を得ています
Ariel mentioned that there is a level of conservatism
アリエルは、あるレベルの保守主義があると述べた
I would like to ask what is discussed in the degree of conservatism
保守主義の度合いで何が議論されているかを聞きたい
Also for entrepreneurship and higher income
起業や高収入にも
Do you have any ideas to explain this?
これを説明するアイデアはありますか?
Conservative attitude
保守的な態度
We have a set of topics
一連のトピックがあります
Just ask him what he thinks about some attitudes in society
社会におけるいくつかの態度についてどう思うか聞いてみましょう
social values
社会的価値観
generally speaking
一般的に言えば
Males are more conservative than females
男性は女性よりも保守的です
less conservative
保守的ではない
working class more conservative
労働者階級のほうが保守的
This is not a unique phenomenon in Taiwan
これは台湾特有の現象ではありません
the whole world is like this
世界全体がこんな感じだ
So I've been talking about generational differences before
先ほども世代の違いについてお話しましたが、
Recently this John Toppings teacher would say
最近、ジョン・トッピングスの先生がこう言っていました。
He thinks the coming of this generation is a class difference
彼はこの世代の到来は階級の違いだと考えている
That's not all class differences
階級の違いはそれだけではない
Politicians everywhere are eager to stir up class differences too
どこの政治家も階級の違いをかき立てようとしている
Because the class differences are very obvious
階級差が歴然としているので
So I'm thinking that this thing is actually
それで私はこれが実際にあると考えています
From the perspective of our academic research
学術研究の観点から
would not like to see such a development
そのような展開は見たくない
Although we will master, record and analyze
マスタリング、記録、分析はしますが、
Then I just said Chen Yi, Mr. Fu
それから私はチェン・イー、ミスター・フーと言いました。
I feel very happy that
とても嬉しいです
This group has always had low family cohesion
このグループは常に家族の結束力が低い
High degree from single bird family
単一の鳥の家族からの高度な学位
low support among friends
友達の間での支持が低い
And I'm talking about significantly lower
そして、私は大幅に低いことについて話しています
This group of people until he was 31 years old
彼が31歳になるまでこのグループ
He is more likely to have a higher income
彼はより高収入である可能性が高い
I think this is an inspiration to everyone
これは皆さんにとってもインスピレーションになると思います
And this is not journalism
そしてこれはジャーナリズムではありません
this is sociology
これは社会学です
This is statistically significant
これは統計的に有意です
And this group of people is not so small
そして、この人々のグループはそれほど小さいものではありません
Only over 9%
わずか9％以上
don't i think it's very interesting
とても面白いと思いませんか
so ask me why
だから理由を聞いてください
That is to say, maybe we are in the process of breaking the impression of the scientific version
つまり、私たちは科学版の印象を打ち破りつつあるのかもしれない
it may be social science
それは社会科学かもしれない
able to contribute to society and some
社会に貢献できるし、
a big element
大きな要素
Mr. Zhou Wei
周薇先生
My surname is Fang
我姓方
I am retired from the Institute of Marine Biology, Sun Yat-sen University
私は中山大学海洋生物学研究所を退職しました。
I remember personal academic orientation
個人的な学問的方向性を覚えています
It is also closely related to statistics
統計学とも密接な関係がある
we do a lot
私たちはたくさんのことをします
Statistical work on this reliquary
この聖遺物箱に関する統計的研究
Then I congratulate you on this very massive one
それでは、この非常に大規模なプロジェクトについておめでとうございます
A trial protocol and study
治験プロトコルと研究
What I'm going to say next are some of my thoughts
これから話すことは私の考えの一部です
Don't dare say it's dialectical or questioning
それが弁証法的だとか疑問的だとはあえて言わないでください
Because although we are all statistics
なぜなら、私たちは皆統計的であるにもかかわらず、
But I think there are a lot of shocks that are new to me
でも初めての衝撃もたくさんあると思います
First of all, the sampling of our relic statistics is
まず第一に、遺物統計のサンプリングは次のとおりです。
There is a stricter specification
より厳しい仕様があります
But I see that your database is very large
しかし、データベースが非常に大きいことがわかりました
thousands of individual cases
何千もの個別のケース
And there's about 20 years of
そして約20年になります
There is no way for us to do such a research
私たちにはそのような研究をする方法はありません
Then I just express a little bit of my feelings
それから私の気持ちを少しだけ表現します
That's because I don't know much about directness research.
それは私が直接性の研究についてあまり知らないからです。
We compare by measurement, by data
測定とデータで比較します
use the tight one
タイトなものを使用してください
Some tests such as variable anti-review
可変アンチレビューなどの一部のテスト
So I may have some misunderstandings and I'm not sure
なので、誤解があるかもしれないし、よくわかりませんが、
Then my first feeling is
そのとき私の最初の気持ちは、
because you were doing this 20 years ago
20年前にもやってたから
A sample like this
こんな感じのサンプル
When you are going to ask questions and send out questionnaires
ご質問やアンケートの送付をする場合
but i guess
でも多分
the tests you did later
後で行ったテスト
In fact, it did not take into account when sampling
実際、サンプリング時には考慮されていませんでした
you need to answer so many questions
たくさんの質問に答える必要があります
That is to say, the question you asked later was
つまり、後であなたが尋ねた質問は、
When the questionnaire was unloaded
アンケートがアンロードされたとき
you actually didn't expect
あなたは実際には期待していませんでした
It was only later from such a large Database
このような大規模なデータベースから取得したのは後になってからです
you generate some motivation
あなたは何らかのモチベーションを生み出します
did some tests
いくつかのテストをしました
So here's what we're talking about
ここで私たちが話していることは次のとおりです
just might be
ただそうかもしれない
Do you measure first and ask for proof
まず測定して証明を求めますか
And then finally some Ni said from it
そして最後に、いくつかのNiがそこから言いました
Then come to tests
それからテストに来てください
This is the same as when we were doing ecology in the wild
これは野生で生態学を行っていたときと同じです
is kind of the opposite
ある意味逆です
Because you mentioned that Ni said it would
ニーがそうするだろうとあなたが言ったから
would in fact be more or less
実際には多かれ少なかれそうだろう
Affect your original experimental design
元の実験計画に影響を与える
Include some that are not randomly sampled
無作為に抽出されていないものも含まれます
or something like that
またはそのようなもの
Then I look at the parsed stuff
それから解析されたものを見ます
also analyzed many
もたくさん分析しました
this different ni said
これは違うと私は言いました
Of course your team is very big
もちろんあなたのチームはとても大きいです
so there are many
だからたくさんあります
many people doing their own thing
自分のことをやっている人がたくさんいる
So this database cannot be a single database
したがって、このデータベースを単一のデータベースにすることはできません
So every member of every team
つまり、すべてのチームのすべてのメンバーが
when he did this test
彼がこのテストをしたとき
He screens the data he needs in it
彼はその中で必要なデータをスクリーニングします
So these data and another team
これらのデータと別のチーム
In fact, the data made will have some differences
実際に作成したデータには多少の違いがあります
So it is impossible to have the same database
したがって、同じデータベースを持つことは不可能です
do all these quizzes you say
あなたが言うこれらのクイズをすべてやってください
because if that's the case
なぜなら、そうであれば
If you have to answer so many questions
たくさんの質問に答えなければならない場合
We're statistically just going to have less degrees of freedom
統計的には自由度が減少するだけです
because you have to answer a lot of questions
たくさんの質問に答えなければならないので
Every time you ask a question, your degree of freedom will be reduced.
質問するたびに自由度が減っていきます。
So even if you have such a large database
したがって、これほど大規模なデータベースがある場合でも、
I feel a little lack of freedom
ちょっと自由度が足りない気がする
Another problem is
もう一つの問題は
I've been trying to guess what statistics you use
あなたがどのような統計を使用しているのか推測しようとしました
I always thought it was because I didn’t understand a lot in the study of direct belief.
最初は、直接信仰の研究ってわからないことだらけだなと常々思っていました。
So it's probably doing direct research to do the test
したがって、テストを行うために直接調査を行っている可能性があります
But then I made a guess
しかし、その後、私は推測しました
You are probably using a method of the so-called maximum likelihood
おそらく、いわゆる最尤法を使用していると思われます。
That's because your data are all frequency
それは、データがすべて周波数であるためです。
So you are doing a test with the highest probability
つまり、最も高い確率でテストを行っていることになります
What about this?
これはどうですか？
I understand a little bit
少しは分かりました
Because there is something in it including logistic test and so on
ロジスティックテストなども入っているので
As for some tests, we usually have an f test
いくつかのテストに関しては、通常は f テストがあります。
a two-tailed test
両側検定
But I saw some results from your test
しかし、あなたのテストの結果をいくつか見ました
Significant or not
重要かどうか
but there are positive and negative
しかし、ポジティブなものとネガティブなものがあります
Then this is a challenge for me
それならこれは私にとっての挑戦です
I never thought of something like edge analysis
エッジ解析のようなことは考えたこともありませんでした
F test in analysis method
分析法におけるF検定
Another conclusion can be drawn from the government
政府からは別の結論が導き出される
This is why I want to go back and go well
だからこそ、戻って元気に行きたいのです
to think for yourself and to learn something
自分で考えて何かを学ぶこと
Another thing is
もう一つのことは、
I'm a little confused
少し混乱しています
Usually we do a test
通常はテストを行います
We all assume that my sampling space is
私たちは皆、自分のサンプリング空間が次のようなものであると想定しています。
is stable
安定しています
is constant
一定です
but the one on your side
でもあなたの側にいる人は
20 years before and after the change
変化の前後20年
Of course you have some test
もちろんテストもあります
very very very correct
とてもとてもとても正しい
Because I want to compare what's 20 years ago with what's 20 years from now
20年前と20年後を比べたいから
but some are
しかし、一部の人は
It seems inevitable that the
それは避けられないと思われます
Assume that during the 20-year period of your study
20年間の研究期間中に次のようになると仮定します。
Society as a whole hasn't changed much
社会全体はあまり変わっていない
Or is he actually stable
それとも本当に安定しているのか
Or maybe he wasn't disturbed too much
それとも、あまり動揺しなかったのかもしれない
but i personally think
でも個人的には思う
Even especially in sociology
特に社会学においても
Our society has not been stable in the past 20 years
過去 20 年間、私たちの社会は安定していませんでした
So many factors outside of me
自分の外にたくさんの要素がある
including gender relations including
男女関係も含めて
some of the things we talk about have actually changed a lot in 20 years
私たちが話していることの中には、実際には 20 年間で大きく変わったものもあります
Actually changing factors
実際に変化する要因
These samples are not self-generated
これらのサンプルは自己生成されたものではありません
but external
しかし外部の
External impact exists
外部からの影響が存在する
This is all my doubts
これが私のすべての疑問です
you don't need to answer thanks
ありがとうと答える必要はありません
This is the last question for us because the Secretariat still has some
事務局からまだ質問が残っておりますので、これで最後の質問とさせていただきます。
something to announce
何か発表すること
thanks for this
これはありがとう
Professor Fang was the senior of my National Taiwan University choir, he was our Tanner
方教授は私の国立台湾大学合唱団の先輩で、私たちのタナーでした。
A great Tanner
偉大なタンナー
You're doing marine research now quite differently than the social sciences
あなたは現在、社会科学とはまったく異なる方法で海洋研究を行っています
But let me put it simply
でも、簡単に言わせてください
Just now Professor Fang specifically mentioned that we are researching on the content of the problem
今、方教授が、問題の内容について研究していると具体的におっしゃいました。
Is it a lot of spur-of-the-moment inspiration?
思いつきのインスピレーションが多いのでしょうか？
I think my answer should say three out of four no
私の答えは 4 つ中 3 つが「ノー」であるべきだと思います
because every time we have a research framework that comes up
毎回研究体制があるので
where to get the topic
どこで話題を得るのか
But you saw me just now I don't look back
でもあなたは今私を見たわ 私は振り返らない
We have some ongoing issues
現在進行中の問題がいくつかあります
Also write some new topics
新しい話題も書きます
In other words, even if it is a discipline group
つまり、規律集団であっても
After we entered university from high school in another country, we changed it a little bit.
私たちは外国の高校から大学に進学してから少し変わりました。
Then we will change it a little after he admits it
そして、彼がそれを認めたら、少し変更します。
Because maybe your parents are not around and will keep asking you
たぶんあなたの両親は近くにいないので、あなたに尋ね続けるでしょう
Who are you hanging out with? I just hope you come home earlier or pay attention to your diet
誰と遊んでるの? 早く帰ってくるか、食事に気を付けてほしいと願うばかりです
We will indeed change the persistent and new questions like these
このような永続的で新しい質問を実際に変更します
The other one is right
もう一つは正しいです
between the authors for each topic
トピックごとに著者間で
his request is different
彼の要求は違う
So he often takes samples, he only makes samples from one country and follows them all the way to the end
そのため、彼は頻繁にサンプルを採取し、1 つの国からのみサンプルを作成し、それを最後まで追跡します。
If it is the sum of one country and three countries
1か国と3か国の合計なら
some say one of the parents
両親の一人がそう言う人もいる
If it's dead, I don't want it
死んでるなら要らないよ
because with your title
なぜなら、あなたのタイトルでは
that denominator you made
あなたが作ったその分母
What you see N will be different
Nが見るものは違うでしょう
Well, in recent years, we hope that everyone will use the same
さて、近年では皆さんも同じものを使っていただければと思います
For example just
たとえばただ
Constructive disguises like that education
教育のような建設的な偽装
General Universities Top Universities Private Universities
一般大学 トップ大学 私立大学
we can all use the same topic
全員が同じトピックを使用できます
Like recently, some reporters seem to visit
最近も何人かの記者が訪れているようだ
Our Professor George made this
私たちのジョージ教授がこれを作りました
depression
憂鬱症
Some research on the sense of rating
評価の感覚に関するいくつかの研究
You will find that everyone uses some of the same topics
誰もが同じトピックをいくつか使用していることがわかります
what about the end
最後はどうですか
In terms of statistics, we have a publication outside
統計に関しては、外部に出版物を発行しています。
Actually, I was just joking with Deputy Huang
実は今、黄副官と冗談を言ったんです。
in our group
私たちのグループでは
probably except me
おそらく私を除いて
Each teaches social statistics
それぞれが社会統計を教えます
So they all know how to use
だからみんな使い方を知っている
are very complicated
とても複雑です
Then I often have to work very hard to follow
その場合、私は従うために非常に一生懸命働かなければならないことがよくあります
I want to say why this topic uses this method
このトピックでなぜこの方法を使用するのかを言いたい
Use this method for that topic
そのトピックにはこのメソッドを使用してください
what's the point
ポイントは何ですか
things like cohabitation
同棲のようなもの
Teacher Yang Wenshan came to my office twice to tell me
ヤン・ウェンシャン先生が私のオフィスに二度来て、私にこう言いました。
I have to listen for a long time to understand
理解するには長時間聞かないといけない
Because they all have their own algorithm
それぞれが独自のアルゴリズムを持っているため、
But he's right, isn't the statistic?
しかし、彼の言うことは正しいのです、統計はそうではありませんか？
we may be with biological
私たちは生物学的存在かもしれない
I heard the creature's leather card is very powerful
クリーチャーの革カードは非常に強力だと聞きました
He ordered everyone to do the same thing
彼は全員に同じことをするように命令した
we have never heard of this
私たちはこれについて聞いたことがありません
the other one is
もう一つは
20 years of change in this social context
この社会情勢における 20 年間の変化
often to inspire us to add some questions
多くの場合、私たちにいくつかの質問を追加するよう促します
For example, when someone asked about the economic bubble in 2008 and 2009
たとえば、2008 年と 2009 年のバブル経済について質問されたとき、
we specifically asked
私たちは具体的に尋ねました
family financial instability
家族の経済的不安定
We have a set of questions that ask you if the following things happened to you last year
昨年、次のようなことがあなたに起こったかどうかを尋ねる一連の質問があります。
Does anyone remember will ask
覚えている人は尋ねます
These include the father's cause, the mother's cause, or one of the parents
これには、父親のキャリア、母親のキャリア、または両親のいずれかが含まれます。
death or divorce etc.
死や離婚など。
I hope to be able to capture this
これで捕獲できるといいですね
special circumstances
特殊事情
but of course
しかし、もちろん
Because after this whole topic goes down,
なぜなら、この話題がすべて終わった後、
you can't move around
動き回ることはできません
Even now we sometimes say how to write like this at that time
今でも時々「あの時はこう書こう」と言うことがあります。
Can't write Chinese well enough
中国語が十分に書けない
you can't change
あなたは変えることができません
because you already use people like this
あなたはすでにこのような人々を使用しているからです
have to keep using it continuously
継続的に使い続けなければならない
So I thank Professor Fang
だからファン教授に感謝します
Remind us something we really still
本当にまだ何かを思い出させてください
I hope that in the future, when others do research,
将来、他の人が研究するときに、
there may be a place to work hard
頑張れる場所はあるかもしれない
Thanks
ありがとう
ok ask again
わかりました、もう一度聞いてください
secretary group
秘書組
what are you announcing
何を発表していますか
thank you before we do this
そうする前にありがとう
Professor Ying's wonderful speech
イン教授の素晴らしいスピーチ
applause
拍手
Secretariat report
事務局報告
Today's speech is by Mr. Yi Xinchun before his retirement
今日の講演は、退任前の李新春氏によるものです。
The last big Chinese speech
中国最後の大演説
Colleague Xu Weisuo in order to thank the teacher
同僚の徐偉蘇が先生に感謝の気持ちを伝える
dedication over the years
長年にわたる献身
Make special use of tonight's occasion
今夜の機会を特別にご利用ください
Thanks Teacher Yi
ありがとうイー先生
We also wish Mr. Yi's retirement life
私たちもイー氏の退職後の生活を祈っています
Still rich and brilliant
それでも豊かで輝かしい
Thanks
ありがとう
Then you can get a small gift
そしたらちょっとしたプレゼントがもらえます
Thank you for your participation today
本日はご参加いただきありがとうございました